（A24影业）
（纽约中央影业）
（九码半）
（八码半）
- Mrs. Mariann. - You have the nine and a half?
- 玛丽安太太 - 是九码半的吗？
- Yeah, you're a lucky lady. - Oh, I'm excited.
- 是的 可给你找到了 - 太好了
Last pair. Let me see those beautiful feet.
最后一双了 来 露个玉足吧
（美国 纽约）
The right foot's all right?
右脚还可以吧？
There you go. Get it in there.
来 用力伸进去
- They're too tight. - It's okay. All right.
- 太小了 - 加油 加油
- Are these the nine and a half? - These are the nine and a half, yeah.
- 这真是九码半？ - 对 九码半
- Do you have the next size? - No, not in a Kerrybrooke.
- 有大一号的吗？ - 唯独这牌子没有
But that's why I don't like Kerrybrooke,
所以我不推荐凯步轩
because they fit really small. They're made for dolls or something.
穿他们鞋 跟裹小脚一样
- They're too tight. - Okay, take 'em off. Don't worry about it.
- 太不合脚了 - 好吧 脱下来吧 脱下来吧
- You ever try Vitality? - No.
- 穿过朝阳吗？ - 没有
- It's a much better model if you want durable leather. - I'll be right with you.
- 这牌子档次更高 更耐穿 - 稍等一下
- Excuse me. Sorry. - I'll try it.
- 打扰了 - 拿来试试吧
I bought a pair of shoes here the other day from him, with the glasses.
我要找前几天卖我鞋的 戴眼镜的那位
- Marty. - Yeah?
- 马蒂 - 怎么了？
This woman said she bought a pair of shoes from you.
有位顾客找你 前几天是你卖她鞋吗？
Oh, yeah. You bought the brown Mary Janes, right?
哦 对 是买了那双棕色玛丽珍吧
- Yeah, I did. They're great. - How do they fit you?
- 没错 鞋挺好的 - 合脚吗？
- I wore them out of the store. - Okay.
- 我当时穿着就走了 - 好
- So I left my old ones here. - Okay. What did they look like?
- 然后旧鞋就落在这里了 - 旧鞋长什么样？
They're two-toned pumps, wingtips.
拼色高跟鞋 带小翅膀图案
- Lloyd, did you see her shoes? - No.
- 洛伊 有见到那鞋吗？ - 没有
Is it possible that you maybe put them in one of the boxes of the other shoes
不会被你们装回我没拿走的鞋盒
that I was trying on and restocked them?
然后又塞回库房了吧？
- Okay. All right. Um... - If I saw the boxes, I'd be able to recognize it.
- 好吧... - 要是看见鞋盒 我就能认出来
Do you mind if my colleague helps you out for a second?
让我同事来帮您选购好吗？
Lloyd. Can you help with Mariann here?
洛伊 你帮忙接待一下这位行吗？
Sure. Sure.
没问题 等下
- Yeah, we'll check the basement. Come. - Thank you. Excuse me.
- 走 跟我去仓库 - 谢谢 借过
- Lloyd's gonna help you. Get the Vitalities. - Okay. I'll think about the price.
- 洛伊会拿来朝阳的 - 好吧 我得考虑下价格
- I'll be right with you. Let me finish up here. - Okay, thank you.
- 您先坐会儿 我马上就来 - 好的 谢谢
- What? - Shh.
- 怎么了？ - 嘘
- Marty. - Ah, fuck.
- 是马蒂吧？ - 是 真倒霉
I wanna show you something. Come here.
给你看个东西 进来一下
- What? - Just get low. Go low.
- 什么？ - 蹲下 赶紧蹲下
Why do I have to get low?
我干嘛非得蹲着啊
- How you doing? - Marty, look what I got for ya.
- 忙吗？ - 马蒂 瞧瞧我给你准备的
What is this?
什么东西？
Check it out.
仔细瞧瞧
（诺金鞋行 家用鞋履 经久耐穿）
What am I looking at?
有啥特别的？
Turn it over.
看看背面
（马蒂·毛瑟 管事）
- Manager? - Manager.
- 做管事？ - 对 管事
Come on, Murray.
得了吧 老默
Whatever you do, just don't tell Lloyd about this.
不管怎样 别告诉洛伊就行
Look, I've been very clear with you. I'm not...
我不是不尊重你 但把话讲明白
trying to be disrespectful. You built something very commendable here.
这店子你经营得确实不错
I don't wanna-- I don't wanna discuss this now.
现在别 别谈这些
Stop. Stop. Let me say something.
别打断我 让我说完
It's been good for my soul to see this up close and personal.
这活确实让我学到不少
- But I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this.
- 但我不是来卖鞋的 - 我不想听这些
- I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this, okay?
- 我不是这块料 - 别扯这些 行吗？
I do wanna discuss it, 'cause when I'm back from my trip, this is over.
必须谈 等我飞回来 我就不干了
I'm not coming back and doing this.
我不可能留在这行
Speaking of which, can we settle up now? I gotta buy my plane ticket.
说到这 工钱现在能结吗 我得去买机票
We'll settle at closing.
打烊再结
I wanted to see the travel agent on my lunch break.
我得趁午休去买票
You'll never come back after your lunch break.
你拿到钱肯定不回来了
That's what you think of me?
你真把我看成那种人？
- Yes. - You think I would go and not come back?
- 对 - 你真以为我会跑了不回来吗？
Yes. I said settle at closing, okay?
对 我说了打烊再结 行吗？
- That's it? - Yeah, that's it. Goodbye.
- 就这样？ - 对 就这样 出去吧
I love you.
你可真会疼人
- Come on. - Wait. Just wait for me.
- 快点 - 等我一下
- I was about... I was about to come to you. - What?
- 我本来就...正要去你家的 - 啥？
No, Ira's home sick.
不行 艾勒在家病着呢
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. I can't get sick. - What?
- 喂喂喂 什么病 别传染给我 - 什么？
I got the championships.
我得去打锦标赛 我可不能病
No, it's food poisoning. It's food poisoning.
不是 他是吃坏肚子了 只是吃坏肚子了
I wish I could hide you in my luggage.
真想把你塞进行李箱带走
I wanna come with you so bad.
我也好想跟你走
♪ Let's dance in style, let's dance for a while ♪
♪ 趁还有机会 跳起来吧 ♪
♪ Heaven can wait, we're only watching the skies ♪
♪ 别靠天命 活在当下吧 ♪
♪ Hoping for the best but expecting the worst ♪
♪ 盼着好事 也做好最坏打算 ♪
♪ Are you gonna drop the bomb or not? ♪
♪ 明天会不会就烟消云散？ ♪
♪ Let us die young or let us live forever ♪
♪ 要么痛快地死 要么好好活下去 ♪
主演
提莫西·查拉梅
♪ We don't have the power but we never say never ♪
♪ 命靠天定 但我们偏要逆流而上 ♪
♪ Sitting in a sandpit, life is a short trip ♪
♪ 潮来潮去 人生苦短啊 ♪
主演
格温妮斯·帕特洛
♪ The music's for the sad men ♪
♪ 能懂这歌的人 也懂我的伤 ♪
主演
敖德萨·阿锡安
♪ Can you imagine when this race is won? ♪
♪ 这场竞赛会怎么收场？ ♪
♪ Turn our golden faces into the sun ♪
♪ 是胜利还是灭亡？ ♪
主演
凯文·奥利里
♪ Praising our leaders, we're getting in tune ♪
♪ 我们唱着赞歌 别无选择 ♪
♪ The music's played by the, the mad man ♪
♪ 魔鬼弹着舞曲 逼我们起舞 ♪
主演
泰勒·奥康马
♪ Forever young ♪
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
《至尊马蒂 · 美国制造》
♪ Forever and ever ♪
♪ 永远永远地活着 ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
反手 反手 反手
Forehand. Forehand. Forehand.
正手 正手 正手
演出
法兰·德瑞雪
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
反手 反手 反手
演出
阿贝尔·费拉拉
Forehand. Forehand.
正手 正手
Backhand. Backhand.
反手 反手
演出
艾莫里·科恩
And lob.
放高球
Forehand.
正手
演出
盖札·罗里格
- Marty! - What!
- 马蒂 - 干嘛
- Phone! - Tell him I left 20 minutes ago!
- 有电话 - 跟他说我20分钟前就走了
I'm not your goddamn messenger! Pick up the goddamn phone!
我才不当你的传声筒 自己去接那该死的电话
演出
佩恩·吉列特
I can't. Wally, take the white shirt off.
我跟不上 沃利 把白衬衫脱了
I can't follow the white ball against the white shirt.
白球配白衬衫 看不清
Stop it. You're a fucking sun dodger.
别找借口 孬种才这样找借口
演出
桑德拉·伯恩哈德
Oh, yeah? I love you. I love you.
我孬种？怎么怕了 怕了？
Hello?
喂
It's Judy.
我是朱迪
演出
川口功人
Hi, Judy.
怎么了 朱迪
Your mother, she's very sick.
你妈病得很重
- Okay, really? - Yes.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
She's gray in the face. She's speaking nonsense.
她脸色苍白 满嘴胡话
演出
拉瑞·拉索·斯洛曼
She's asking for you. You should come home.
她一直喊你 你得赶快回家一趟
Sounds really bad. You should probably call an ambulance.
听上去不行了 你们赶紧叫救护车吧
演出
卢克·曼利
Who's gonna go with her?
谁陪她去啊
Uh, I don't know. You should probably go since you're so invested.
我不知道 你这么上心 你陪她去呗
Hold on a minute.
等一下 别挂
He's not buying it.
他不吃这套
Just tell him I stopped breathing!
跟他说我断气了
（至尊马蒂 美国制造）
Absolutely not. That's ridiculous. I'm not saying that.
绝对不行 太严重了 我不能这么说
Tell him you're taking me to the hospital.
跟他说你正急着送我去医院
Okay, fine. I'll take her to the emergency room
好吧 我得赶紧把她送去急诊
and sit there and wait for God knows how long.
然后在那儿陪着 天知道要陪多久
And you can come here and give my husband his medicine
你来负责伺候我丈夫 给他喂药
and massage his feet all night long.
“晚上给他翻身做按摩”
Tell him I passed out.
“跟他说我晕倒了”
配乐
丹尼尔·洛帕汀
- Oh, my God! Your mother, she just lost consciousness. - Hi, sweetheart.
- “天呐 你妈刚刚昏过去了” - 你好啊 小姑娘
You've gotta come home now.
“你现在赶紧回家”
Hello?
谁啊
Hi. Just give me a second.
是我 饭马上好
I don't know what you want me to say, Judy.
“朱迪 别闹了行吗”
I'm busy. I'm on my lunch break.
“我正忙着 连午饭都还没吃呢”
I can hear her whispering. She's right there standing next to you.
“我妈就在你旁边指挥 我都听得见”
- I told you she passed out. - It's annoying me now.
- “我都说她昏过去了” - “别来烦我了”
Who are you talking to?
跟谁通话呢？
Oh. I'm not talking to anybody.
哦 没人
Judy's just been tying up the line for an hour.
朱迪一直占着电话好久了
I got you some broth.
我给你买了点热饭
剪辑
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
It's ice cold.
都凉透了
- Yeah, 'cause the line was really long at the shop. - Oh, yeah?
- 买饭排了好久 买回来都凉了 - 你都不打草稿？
So that's what they'll say if I call down and ask?
信不信我现在打电话去核实？
You don't believe me? You calling me a liar?
你要是觉得我骗你
Pick up the phone and call them.
你就打电话核实去
- You're gonna have to get Judy off the phone first. - Oh, okay.
- 不过看你怎么打 朱迪在占着电话 - 喔 行
Hey, Judy, get off the phone.
喂 朱迪 把电话给我挂掉
摄影
达吕斯·康第
Okay, this is a normal IATT approved ball.
看 这颗是国际乒联标准球
【国际乒乓球联合会:1926年成立 主管国际乒乓球赛事和规则】
Try to follow the white ball against the white.
盯紧这颗白球
Almost impossible, right?
在白背景下挺难的吧
I don't even see your eyes moving.
你眼珠都没动
If I'm wearing a white shirt, you can't see the ball.
要是我穿白衬衫 你连球都看不到
Now, imagine it with an orange ball, which no one's ever thought of.
换颗橙球试试 这是我自个儿想出来的
See? You're already following it way better. Look at his eyes.
看吧 你盯得多牢 瞧他那眼神
- See how his eyes are looking? - Yeah, I see it.
- 看见没？ - 嗯 看见了
You're looking more engaged now.
你现在盯得更紧了
So that's what we wanna do. Right now in the world of table tennis,
这就是机遇所在 目前桌球界
【桌球:英语中乒乓球亦称“桌上网球” 简称桌球】
you're obliged to wear black, just so you can follow the white ball.
为了盯住白球都得穿黑衣
- Look at this. That's Ted Bailey. - Who's that?
- 看看这个 这是泰德·贝利 - 他是谁？
【桌上网球为正式运动称谓 乒乓球偏休闲用语】
That's ex-number one ranked player in the world right now.
他曾是英国冠军 世界第一
He's the British champion. I've already beat him, by the way.
已经被我打败了
Now look at this.
再看这个
That's Jack Kramer, number one tennis player.
网球界第一杰克·克雷默
【杰克·克雷默:40-50年代著名网球手 推动网球精英化】
- What's the difference there? - He's wearing all white.
- 有啥区别？ - 他穿的是全白
He's in all white. It's beautiful.
对 一身白 很绅士
【50年代网球为绅士运动 桌上网球(乒乓球)尚非主流】
To me, that's luxury. To me, that's class. You could sell that.
这叫品味 这叫格调 这是卖点
Marty, a custom ball like that is gonna cost a lot of money.
马蒂 这种定制球得花不少钱
Of course it's custom. It's an original ball for an original guy.
当然得定制 奇人配奇球
It's the Marty Supreme ball, not the Marty Normal ball.
这是至尊马蒂牌 不是平庸马蒂牌
But what's it gonna cost?
你算过成本吗？
It doesn't matter the cost. We can't cheap out on this.
钱不重要 咱别抠门
It's gonna be nominal, Mr. Galanis.
花不了多少钱的 加拉尼斯先生
You always said we gotta spend money to make money, right?
你不是老说先花钱才能赚钱吗
制片人
提莫西·查拉梅
Get me a cup of coffee.
给我端杯咖啡来
No. Get your secretary to get ya a cup of coffee.
没门 让你秘书去弄
Nancy's busy. Just get me a coffee.
南希忙着呢 你去弄吧
Dad, we're talking like men about business here.
才不 我正像大人那样谈生意
- I'm not getting ya a cup of coffee. - Get me the damn coffee!
- 我才不给你端咖啡 - 赶紧去给老子端咖啡去
制片人
安东尼·卡塔格斯
Marty, you want a coffee?
马蒂 也给你来一杯？
No, I'm all right. I'm not drinking caffeine.
谢谢 不用了 我不碰咖啡因
Listen.
听着
I appreciate you're friends with my son.
我感谢你和我儿子的这份交情
He's limited.
但他不成器
He's 30 years old. He's still living at home.
30岁还靠爹吃饭
He hasn't done much.
没啥名堂
And he doesn't know business. He doesn't know the costs.
他也不懂做生意 就会乱花钱
I don't think he's limited, Mr. Galanis, respectfully.
恕我直言 盖拉尼斯先生 我不觉得他不成器
I mean, look at your business success.
看看您做生意的本事
That's in your DNA, and you passed that through to Dion.
那是刻在骨子里的 迪翁也有
- It just hasn't been awoken yet. - I don't know.
- 只是还没显露出来 - 谁知道呢
I wouldn't be here trying to involve you in something that I
我要是没把握
制片人
伊莱·布什
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
didn't fully in my bones believe in.
我也不会拉您入伙的
And I have tremendous respect for your money. I know it's hard to believe,
我很尊重您的钱 说来您可能不信
but I'm telling you, this game, it fills stadiums overseas.
但这门运动在国外是火得不得了
And it's only a matter of time before it fills stadiums in the United States too,
在美国火起来也只是时间问题
before I'm staring at you from the cover of a Wheaties box.
到时候我的广告会铺天盖地
I- I don't know nothing about this business.
我 我对这行一窍不通
No, you don't. That's why you gotta trust me.
确实不通 所以更该信我
This time next week, I'll be the first American to ever win the British Open.
下周这个时候 我就是首位赢下英国公开赛的美国人
编剧
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
That'll slide me into the number one ranking for the World Championship.
到时候我就能一路杀到世锦赛 然后拿下世界第一
Life magazine's gonna cover it. Look magazine's gonna cover it.
到时候《生活》和《展望》都会报道
They have to. The editor of Look magazine, he loves me. They all love me.
这是板上钉钉的事 《展望》就在捧我 他们都会捧我
I'm uniquely positioned to be the face of the entire sport in the United States.
到时候我就是这项运动在美国的唯一代言人
导演
乔什·萨弗迪
（家庭鞋履）
Lloyd!
洛伊
I'm closing up.
我要打样
Yeah, I can see that. Just here to see my uncle.
我知道 我来找我舅
He left.
他走了
He left? What do you mean he left? For the day?
走了？你什么意思？不回来了？
He had to take your mother to the hospital.
他得带你妈去医院
For crying out loud. She's not sick.
别闹了 她根本没病
Hey, Lloyd, he owes me money. We were supposed to settle up today.
洛伊 他还欠我工钱 说好了今天结清
Well, maybe if you didn't take that five-hour lunch,
要不是你午休了五个钟头
- you would have spoke with him. - Oh, shut up.
- 兴许就能见着他 - 闭嘴吧你
- Hello. - You're sounding a lot better, huh? That happened quick.
- 谁呀 - 吃了什么狗皮膏药 好得挺快的啊
I'll live, no thanks to you!
我会挺过去的 别指望我靠你
Enough, Mom. Are you with Murray? Be honest.
妈 别扯了 默里舅在你那儿吗？别骗我
No. I think he left for his trip. Okay?
没有 但他好像准备出趟远门
His trip? What trip?
出哪门子的远门？
He's taking Esther to Kutchers for the weekend.
他带着埃丝特要去库彻度假村过周末
- When this... - But he would have stayed if I asked him to.
- 这算什么啊 - 只要我一句话 他就会留下
You're not sick, Mom. He was supposed to give me my money for my flight.
你根本没病 妈 他答应给我机票钱的
Well, I don't know anything about that, sweetie.
孩子 那事我可不知道
Yes, you do! Why do you think I'm working here?
别装蒜 否则我干嘛干这活？
I literally only accepted this job for that.
我就是为了挣那笔钱
I have no idea what you are implying.
我可比窦娥还冤
- You know what this is? - What, what is this?
- 你知道你在干嘛吗？ - 我在干嘛？
This is sabotage. You're sabotaging me.
你在毁我 你在毁我前程
Oh, please. You're sabotaging your own life.
别扯了 你是在自毁前程
- What is that? - What?
- 那是什么？ - 什么？
Are you seriously thinking I'm gonna rob you?
你竟然觉得我要抢你？
Just a reflex.
职业反应
If I wanted to rob you, you'd be dead. You'd be in a pool of blood.
我要真想抢你 你早死在血泊里了
I came to grab my suit. You know I bought this specifically for my trip?
我是来拿西装的 这是我特地为这趟比赛买的
Didn't know you need a suit to play ping pong.
打小乒乓还要穿西装 真长见识了
【乒乓:1950年代“乒乓”在部分场合带有嘲讽意味】
【从事这项运动常被歧视 被视为不务正业】
I just want the $700 that Murray owes me.
我就要老默欠我的那700块
【约合2026年 8,600美元 6万人民币 26万新台币】
Yeah, or what?
不然呢？
- Or I'm gonna shoot you in the leg. - No you're not.
- 不然我就往你腿上来一枪 - 你不敢
You sure about that?
你敢赌吗？
You shoot me in the leg, you'll be spending the next few years in jail.
你要是打我腿 你未来几年都得坐牢
Okay, I'll shoot you in the head instead.
行 那我就朝你脑门开枪
You're not gonna do that either.
你没那胆子
Look, Lloyd, I just want what was promised to me, not a penny more.
洛伊 听我说 我只拿走我的那700 绝不多拿
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that amount in prize money.
回来我会带回十倍奖金
So just turn the other cheek, let me take what I'm owed,
睁只眼闭只眼吧 让我拿走欠我的
and I'll give you an even $100 dollars when I get back.
等我回来给你整整100
【约1,230美元 8,600人民币 3.7万新台币】
Not interested.
不干
Lloyd, come on. Look at me, please.
洛伊 别这样 转过来
We both know you'd love nothing more than to see my ass get canned.
咱俩都清楚 你巴不得看我卷铺盖走人
You're a thousand times more motivated than me to do this job,
你干这行的劲头比我大千万倍
and yet look at this, okay?
可你看看吧
Look.
看看
Murray gave that to me. Flip it over.
老默给我的 看看背面
Manager. I'm gonna be your boss!
管事 我要当你管事了
How unfair is that? I could fire you whenever I want.
公平吗？我能把你扫地出门
I could tell you to sweep the floor on your hands and knees.
还能叫你跪着扫地
How about that, okay?
任我差遣
Lloyd, I'm actually pointing a gun at you right now.
洛伊 我真拿枪指着你
I'm actually threatening to use it.
真的在威胁你
This is a legit robbery like any other. My fingerprints are all over this thing.
这是实打实的抢劫 枪上有我的指纹
These are facts.
这都是铁证
So open the safe, let me take what I'm owed,
把钱柜打开 把该我的给我
and you can call Murray, tell him exactly what happened,
回头你照实跟老默说
get me fired, press charges. Whatever you want, okay?
想把我轰走还是告我都随你 行吗？
Fine.
行
- Here you go, sir. - Thank you.
- 给您 先生 - 谢谢
♪ The time I like is the rush hour ♪
♪ 我爱高光时刻 ♪
♪ 'Cause I like the rush ♪
♪ 我爱人群喧嚣 ♪
♪ The pushing of the people ♪
♪ 人群拥挤又吵闹 ♪
You son of...
垃圾
♪ I like it all so much ♪
♪ 我就沉浸其中 ♪
♪ Such a mass of motion ♪
♪ 人潮蜂拥涌过来 ♪
♪ Do not know where it goes ♪
♪ 谁晓得要去哪儿 ♪
♪ I move with the movement ♪
♪ 我随人群往前走 ♪
We don't get our own rooms?
还没有单间吗？
（英国 伦敦）
♪ And I have the touch ♪
♪ 尽情享受这感觉 ♪
It's freezing in here.
这里还冷得要死
I really need you to be serious now. Eyes on me.
现在给我正经点儿 眼睛看这里
Pakistan, I need you to look at me.
巴基斯坦 看这里
Wait, Japan brought a team this year? You see that?
日本今年也派队来了？瞧见没？
Yeah. The Japs sent a team.
是啊 小日本也来了
What about the travel ban?
出境管制呢？
【1952年随盟军移交日本主权 出入境管制开始放宽】
- They must have lifted it. - No more travel ban?
- 肯定解禁了 - 出境管制解除了？
Okay, gentlemen, I want you to flip your paddles for me now.
各位 现在把球拍翻过来 露出国旗
Thank you very much.
谢谢配合
Here we go. One. Two. Three.
准备 一 二 三
♪ Shake those hands ♪
♪ 握个手吧 ♪
Hold it still.
别动
♪ Shake those hands ♪
♪ 握个手吧 ♪
♪ Shake hands ♪
♪ 握手 ♪
（第一场）
♪ Shake hands ♪
♪ 握手 ♪
Match point, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 赛点
【赛点:率先达到者只需再得一分即可赢下整场比赛】
【1950年代乒乓球普遍采用每局21分制 比赛多为五局三胜】
Match, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 胜出
You let me get to my forehand too much. Should've tried to put me in my backhand.
你给我太多正手机会了 应该逼我打反手
【正手/反手:在乒乓球中正手利于进攻 反手偏防守】
Point, Endo.
远藤 得分
- What's the score here? - Nineteen-four.
- 几比几了？ - 19比4
- The Japanese guy? - Japanese guy's trashing Bailey.
- 日本人领先？ - 那日本小子在揍烂贝利
What's he using? What's that paddle?
他手里是什么？那是什么球拍？
I don't know, mate. No one knows.
不知道 没人见过
It's silent.
没声音
- Like a ghost! - Wow.
- 静得出奇 - 哇
Fuck, Bailey.
贝利 好好打
Point, Endo.
远藤 得分
Match point.
赛点
（第三场）
Two games.
还剩两局
21-9.
21比9
- Great game. - Great game, Marty.
- 打得好 - 打得好 马蒂
Match, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 胜出
The winners of the tournament at Stockholm...
那些在斯德哥尔胜出的人...
Hey. You're Ram Sethi, right?
嘿 你是拉姆·塞西吧
Sorry, could you hold for a moment?
抱歉 您先等会儿
- You don't mind? - No. Can I help you with something?
- 你不介意吧？ - 请说 你有啥事？
I was just curious, where are you staying while you're in town?
打听个事 你们住在哪家酒店？
- What business is it of yours? - No.
- 这关你什么事？ - 没事
I'm just saying, what hotel are you staying at?
就是随便打听下
All the IATT representatives are stationed at the Ritz.
国际乒联的官员都住丽兹酒店
- At the Ritz? Yeah, that's what I heard. - Yes.
- 丽兹酒店？别人也这么说 - 对
- Do you think that's okay? - I don't know what you're implying.
- 就这么定了 你没意见吧？ - 什么就这么定了？
- Have you seen where they put me? - Is it a problem?
- 你见过我住的那地方吗？ - 有啥问题吗？
Well, with all due respect, sir, it's a dump.
客气说 那地方就是个狗窝
I'm so sorry it doesn't meet your high standards.
很抱歉没有让你满意
We offer complimentary housing to all our players, Mr. Mauser.
我们这儿给所有选手都是统一标准
So far as I know, you're the only one to complain.
你是唯一一个来这抱怨的
You're talking to me like I'm any player off the street, okay?
你这口气 别把我当普通选手 好吗？
I need good rest so I can win the tournament.
我得休息好 才能赢下比赛
You know perfectly well what an American win will do for the future of the sport.
你很清楚美国人赢对这项运动的好处
- I'm good for table tennis, Mr. Sethi. - Appeal to the USTTA.
- 我就是未来桌球的代言人 - 那就向美乒协反映呗
There is no USTTA. The USTTA is two guys and a desk. It doesn't exist.
美乒协有用吗？他们整个机构就那俩人
- Well, that's not my problem. - It is your problem.
- 那就不归我管了 - 就归你管
I wanna stay where you're staying! That's what I need!
我要住你住的那家酒店 就这么简单
I am finding this whole exchange really offensive.
您这番言论实在是太失礼了
- You're offended? - I am offended.
- 我失礼？ - 对 您失礼
I'm offended! You're making your star player huddle in a rat's ass!
你们才失礼呢 让明星选手住狗窝
I'm so sorry for that interruption.
抱歉刚才被打断了
Um, back to Ceylon and Mexico...
那咱们接着说锡兰和墨西哥的事...
- This is a nice hotel. Must cost a mint. - Yeah, very nice.
- 这酒店真不赖 肯定很贵 - 是啊 确实不错
The IATT covers accommodations?
是国际乒联报销的吗？
- Only for their star players. - Is that right? How many are there?
- 明星选手才有这种待遇 - 是吗？那有多少名啊
Star players? I don't know. I haven't seen any others, so one.
明星选手？不知道 听说就一个
Any nerves, going into the semis?
进半决赛了 紧张吗？
Nerves? Against Kletzki? No. You kidding me?
紧张？对阵克莱茨基？别闹了
Well, he's won the tournament for the last three years.
他曾连续三年夺冠
- He's got quite the reputation. - I have quite the reputation.
- 他名气可不小 - 我名气也不小
Look, I'm gonna do to Kletzki what Auschwitz couldn't.
奥斯维辛集中营都办不到的事 我要办成
Okay. I'm gonna finish the job.
看我怎么把他灭了
【奥斯维辛:纳粹设立的集中营 实施种族灭绝】
- Jesus Christ. - A little strong, mate.
- 天呐 - 这话有点过了
It's all right. I'm Jewish. I can say that.
没事的 我能说 我也是犹太人
In fact, if you think about it, I'm like Hitler's worst nightmare.
事实上你想想 我更像是希特勒的大噩梦
And why's that?
此话怎讲？
Look at me. I'm here.
看看我 我活得好好的
I did it, I'm on top. I'm the ultimate product of Hitler's defeat.
还混到了上层 我就是希特勒失败的最终证明
Yeah, write that down. That was good. Write that down.
对 把这句话记下来 都记下来
- Nice one. - "Ultimate product of Hitler's defeat."
- 不错 - “希特勒失败的最终证明”
- Do you like that confidence? - Put that under a picture of me.
- 你总是那么自信吗？ -一定把那这句放在我照片下面
- Tell us a bit about your background. - My background?
- 来谈谈你的出身吧 - 我的出身？
No, but seriously... My my my mother died in childbirth.
不过说真的 我...我妈死于难产
My father was a compulsive loser who abandoned me when I was two years old.
我爸就是个没出息的人 我两岁时他就丢下我走了
I got stuck in the New York City orphanage system,
我被纽约孤儿院来回折腾
got shuttled from one hellhole to the next.
到处被赶来赶去
- Naturally, got in trouble with the law. - Isn't that Kay Stone?
- 难免有了案底 - 那不是凯·斯通吗？
I don't want any of that to define me.
那破事可不能定义我
Excuse me. Excuse me. What?
采访呢 采访呢 看什么呢？
- It's Kay Stone over there. - That's her.
- 看凯·斯通 - 就是她
Who's that?
谁？
Well, you know, the movie actress. Like, from the 1930s.
三十年代那阵儿的老牌女星
- Opportunities. - Opportunities?
- 演《机缘巧合》的那个 - 《机缘巧合》?
- That was good. - Yeah, yeah. Great movie.
- 演得很好 - 是啊 佳片一个
- Black Box. - My dad loved her.
- 还有《黑匣子》 - 我爸特喜欢她
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 是啊 - 没错
- She was big? - She was huge.
- 她当年很红吗？ - 红透半边天
Came and went. That's her.
后来销声匿迹了
- That's Hollywood, mate. - Yeah. It's her.
- 好莱坞就是这样 - 真是她
It is indeed.
确实是她
Something about a lake?
还有个什么湖的电影
- Shadow Lake. - Yeah, that was good.
- 《影湖》 - 嗯 那片也不错
- Pretty. - Great legs.
- 漂亮 - 腿不错
Gorgeous, mate. Gorgeous.
太漂亮了 太漂亮了
- Think I have a chance, lads? - No.
- 她是在看我吗？ - 不是
I think she's looking Mauser.
她肯定在看毛瑟
Next question.
好了 下个问题
Hello?
喂
- Kay? - Speaking.
- 凯吗？ - 有事吗？
Hey, it's Marty Mauser. I'm in the Royal Suite.
嘿 我是马蒂·毛瑟 我住在皇家套房
I saw you in the lobby yesterday.
我昨天在大堂见过你
Okay.
怎么了？
Yeah, we made eye contact. I was being interviewed.
我们互相看了一眼 当时我在接受采访
- I don't recall. - Well...
- 我不记得了 - 这么说吧
I'm a huge admirer.
我非常仰慕您
Okay. Can I help you with something?
那好吧 要是没事我就挂了
Maybe. I just ordered one of everything off the room service menu.
有点事 我刚把客房餐单上每样都点了一份
There's no way I'll be able to eat it all alone.
我一个人肯定吃不完
Ah.
我懂了
So you'd like me to come up to your room?
所以你想让我去你房间？
- Mm-hmm. Yeah. - Perhaps I should send my husband instead.
- 嗯 没错 - 要不我派我丈夫去吧
Sure. He can come up here, and I'll come down to you.
好啊 他来这里 我去你那里
- Okay, wonderful. Thank you. Goodbye. - Wait. I wanna keep talking.
- 真一套套的 行了 再见 - 等等 我还想再说会儿
Why is that?
说什么？
Because I've never talked to an actual movie star.
我从没跟真正的电影明星说过话
Well, now you have. I hope the experience was all you thought it would be.
现在你说过了 希望你如愿以偿了
You know, I'm something of a performer too.
我其实也喜欢当焦点
- Are you? - Yeah. You don't believe me?
- 是吗？ - 是啊 你不信吗？
I...
我...
You... What? What?
你怎么？怎么了嘛？
You're a performer?
你会演戏？
Yeah, I am a performer. You got the Daily Mailin front of you?
对 会演 你手边有《每日邮报》吗？
Uh, I do have it. Yes?
还真有 怎么了？
Okay. Well, turn to page 12.
好的 那你翻到第12页
Uh...
等下
Page 12.
第12页
Okay. What am I looking at here?
好了 看什么？
Down the middle, in the center.
看中间 正中间
This is you?
那人是你？
Yeah, "the chosen one." It's a nice picture, right?
对“天选之子” 拍得不错吧？
Ping pong?
打小乒乓的？
（真是天选之子？）
I play table tennis. I'm here competing in the British Open.
我打的是桌球 来这儿参加英国公开赛
- How old are you? - I'm 23.
- 你多大了？ - 我23
Twenty-three.
才23岁
Yeah.
嗯
I bet you can't name one film I've done.
我赌你都说不上来我演过什么吧
What makes you say that?
凭啥这么肯定？
Because I stopped acting before you were born.
因为我在你出生前就不演了
- Really? That's really interesting. - Mm-hmm.
- 是吗？有点意思 - 嗯
Kay, did you use my razor to shave your legs?
凯 你拿我的刮胡刀刮腿毛了吗？
- It's dull. I've cut myself. - No.
- 刀钝了 我都划伤了 - 没拿
- Who's that? Your husband? - Mm-hmm.
- 谁在说话？你丈夫？ - 嗯
I guess someone must've snuck in and chopped wood with it.
难不成还有人偷偷溜进来用过它？
- I'm on the phone. - Holy shit.
- 我正打电话呢 - 天呐
- With whom? - Debbie.
- 跟谁打？ - 黛比
- Debbie. - Debbie?
- 黛比 - 黛比？
Tell her to get a life.
叫她少管闲事
- Is he gone? - Mm-hmm.
- 他走了吗？ - 嗯
Okay.
行
So, why'd you stop acting? Let's talk about that.
那你为啥不演了？说说吧
You know, I really have to go.
我还有事 我得挂了
You must miss it, don't you? Come watch me play at Wembley tomorrow.
明天来温布利看我打球吧 你肯定会喜欢的
I... I can't.
我...我去不了
Come on. You can watch me dethrone the number one ranked player in the world.
来吧 看看我怎么战胜世界第一
I'm not available.
我没空
Oh, yeah? What you got going on?
哦哟？你能有什么事？
Actually, I have a big promotional event to attend to for my husband.
有个大宣传会 我得陪我丈夫撑场子
Oh, okay.
哦 好吧
What's he promoting?
宣传什么？
Pens.
笔
- Pens? Are you serious? - Pens.
- 卖笔？开什么玩笑 - 就是笔
- Like, writing pens? - Yes.
- 写字用的笔？ - 对
What, like, he's a pen salesman?
他就是个卖笔的？
How can you afford the suite you're in?
你们怎么住得起这种套房？
He owns Rockwell Ink.
他是罗克韦尔墨业的老板
Oh. Okay. Well...
哦 那好吧...
Yes.
是的
- I know Rockwell Ink. - I'm sure you do.
- 我听说过罗克韦尔墨业 - 你肯定知道
Okay.
好吧
Well, what's the event?
那活动内容是什么？
He's hired Agatha Christie to sign books at Hatchards.
他请了阿加莎·克里斯蒂去哈查兹书店签名售书
【阿加莎·克里斯蒂为英国知名小说家 哈查兹为伦敦老牌书店】
Ooh.
哦 哦
That sounds really boring.
听着就无聊
Okay.
行了
Oh, for God's sake.
哦 没完没了了
- What is it? - Don't hang up, don't hang up. Just one question.
- 有完没完？ - 别挂 别挂 问你个事
Does your room face the street or the courtyard?
你房间是朝街还是朝院子？
I don't know.
不知道
Just answer the question. Is it facing the street or the courtyard?
直说 朝街还是院子？
- The courtyard. - Okay.
- 朝院子 - 好
I need you to go to the window.
去窗边看看
What floor are you on?
你住几楼？
I'm on the third floor, I believe.
三楼吧
Third floor. Okay, perfect.
三楼 好 正好
Look across the street.
朝对面看看
You see the open window with a bowl of fruit on the table?
看见对面那开窗 桌上有果盘的屋了吗？
- You see it? - I do.
- 看到了吗？ - 看到了
Here's what's gonna happen. I'm gonna make an apple appear in that bowl.
看好了 我会让那果盘里凭空多出一个苹果
And if I do, you're gonna blow off your little rendezvous
要是我办到了 你就推掉你那场会
- No, no, no. - and come watch me play.
- 不 不 不 - 来看我比赛
I'm not agreeing to anything, no.
我不会答应任何事
You don't have to agree to anything. I'm gonna do it anyway.
你不用答应 但看好了
Okay? One...
看到了 一
two...
二
three.
三
I'll leave a ticket for you at the box office.
票我留售票处 你去取
（半决赛）
Mauser. Nineteen to five
马蒂·毛瑟 19比5
Point, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Twenty to five.
20比5
Kletzki trails Mauser two games to nil.
克莱茨基整场落后两局 零局比二
Game and match point, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 局点兼赛点
【局点兼赛点:表示马蒂再得一分即可赢下整场比赛】
- Let's have a little fun with this one. - Okay.
- 咱们找点乐子玩玩 - 好吧
- Have a little fun, all right? - Gotcha.
- 玩出花样来 - 收到
Service switches to Kletzki.
换克莱茨基发球
Point, Kletzki.
克莱茨基 得分
Very well, gentlemen. Thank you for that. Thank you.
好的 诸位 谢谢大家 谢谢大家
Kletzki serves 6-20.
克莱茨基发球 当前局分6比20
Mauser leads two games to zero.
马蒂·毛瑟整场领先两局 两局比零
Match point again for Mr. Mauser.
又是马蒂·毛瑟的赛点
Your service again, Kletzki.
再次由你发球 克莱茨基
Point, Mauser!
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Mauser wins the game and match by 21-6. Three games to nil.
马蒂·毛瑟以21比6赢下此局 以三局比零赢下整场比赛
Mauser's on to the finals where he will face Koto Endo of Japan.
马蒂·毛瑟进入决赛 将对阵日本选手远藤功人
（菜单）
Get whatever you want. Don't even look at the prices, okay?
别去看价钱 想吃什么随便点
What are you getting?
你点什么？
I'm gonna get the Beef Wellington and the caviar tasting plate
我就来个威灵顿牛排和鱼子酱拼盘
because they're the most expensive items on the menu.
要点就点最贵的
Listen, I would like to keep going back a little bit about the Globetrotters.
我想再唠叨两句关于巡回表演队的事
- About the Harlem Globetrotters, again? - Yes.
- 哈林篮球队那事儿？ - 对
【哈林篮球队:美国巡回表演篮球队 擅长花式竞技与表演】
- I told you, I'm not interested. - Why not?
- 我跟你说过了 我不干 - 为什么？
'Cause I don't wanna do it.
就是不想干
It's great money.
报酬很高
And we will travel all over the world. Have you seen Venice?
咱们还能环游世界 你不想去威尼斯吗？
- I don't wanna be doing trick shots for a halftime show - Sydney?
- 我才不会去当马戏团的中场把戏 - 悉尼呢？
- while people are going to the bathroom. - Barcelona?
- 观众上厕所时上场 - 巴塞罗那？
That's beneath me, okay?
真丢人 明白吗？
- They're treated like royalty. - Where's the waiter?
- 观众相当捧他们的 - 服务员在哪儿呢？
- Listen, I know people who have done this. - Excuse me.
- 我有个熟人干过这行 - 服务员
Excuse me.
服务员
It's a great opportunity. We should not miss it.
机会难得 咱们得把握住
Marty.
马蒂
Yes, sir. May I help you, sir?
先生 请问需要帮助吗？
Hi. Can we order?
可以点菜了吗？
Of course, sir. Let me fetch your waiter.
没问题 我马上去叫这桌的服务员来
- Hang on. - Yes.
- 别走 - 请说
Uh, I'll be taking care of the Rockwell tab tonight.
今晚罗克韦尔的账由我来结
Put it on my room. The Royal Suite. Marty Mauser.
把账记我房间上 皇家套房 马蒂·毛瑟
- And make sure they know it's me, too. - I will. Leave it to me, sir.
- 跟他们交代清楚 是我付的账 - 明白 先生
- Don't take no for an answer. - I won't.
- 不许被回绝 - 没问题
- Marty Mauser. Royal Suite. Go tell 'em. - Will do, sir.
- 马蒂·毛瑟 皇家套房 去告诉他们 - 好的 先生
Okay. Look at me. Don't look there. Look at me.
行了 看着我 别往那儿瞅 看着我
- Who's Rockwell? - Some bozo.
- 罗克韦尔是谁啊 - 就个傻瓜
Look over now. Be subtle about it. What's he doing?
现在看过去 别太明显 告诉我他在干啥？
He hasn't been here before, sir.
抱歉先生 他之前没来过我们酒店
He's looking at us.
他在看这边
- Really? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
Okay, keep talking to me. Be normal.
好 继续跟我说话 别露馅
Okay, fine. I want you to reconsider.
好吧 听我说 再考虑一下
We would be a great team. I wanna do this with you.
我们会是绝佳组合 我想跟你搭档
Why are you so fixed on the Harlem Globetrotters?
干嘛老想着哈林篮球队？
It's very sad what they do, okay?
那群人干的真丢人
Some of the premier athletes on the planet reduced to acting like circus clowns.
本该是顶尖的运动员却成了杂耍的小丑
What's he doing now?
再看看什么情况
- He's coming towards us. - He's coming?
- 他正朝这桌走来 - 他来了？
- Just be normal. Act casual. - Okay, fine. Okay.
- 别紧张 表现得自然点 - 行 好的 明白
Excuse me. Do I know you?
劳驾 我认识你吗？
I don't think so.
应该不认识
And you wanna buy dinner for my entire table tonight?
你居然想请客？
- Yeah. Is it okay? - Why?
- 对 可以吗？ - 为什么？
What do you mean, why? Do I need a reason?
什么叫为什么？我还需要理由？
Let me rephrase that. What do you want?
我换个说法 你图什么？
No, I don't want anything. It's just my small way of saying thank you.
不 我什么都不图 只是想表示点谢意
- Thank you? - Yeah.
- 谢我？ - 对
Thank me for what, specifically?
具体谢我什么？
For all your products.
谢谢您那些产品
I mean, where would we be without pens?
没了你们的笔 世界该怎么办？
You know, I have many talents, but the one I'm most proud of
你看 我有不少本事 但最得意的就是
- is the ability to smell bullshit from a mile away. - No,
- 能大老远闻出屁话 - 不
I'm being completely sincere.
我说的都是真心话
- Where are you from? - New York. What about you?
- 你是哪儿人？ - 纽约人 你呢？
New York too. What do you do?
也是纽约 你是做什么的？
I'm a professional athlete.
我是个职业运动员
- Really? What sport? - Table tennis.
- 真的吗 哪项运动？ - 桌上网球
Table tennis? That's a sport?
桌球？这也算运动？
Of course it is. I'm here competing in the British Open.
当然算 我来参加英国公开赛的
I'm playing at Wembley tomorrow
我明天要在温布利打决赛
in front of a sold-out crowd in the finals against Japan.
对阵日本 明天赛场座无虚席
- I'm here representing the United States. - Wait, wait, wait.
- 我代表美国出赛 - 等一下
Japan? Japan has a team here?
日本？日本也来了？
- That's what I just said. - How'd they get around the travel ban?
- 我刚才不是说了吗 - 那出境管制呢？
Because table tennis is the fastest growing sport in Asia.
因为桌球在亚洲增长最快
It's huge over there.
在那边火得不行
Oh, you're gonna like this.
说个有意思的事
Do you know what they call their grip? The way they hold their rackets?
你知道他们怎么握拍的吗？
- No. - They call it penholder.
- 不知道 - 他们管那叫直笔握拍
【直拍:起源日本 英文含“握笔”之意】
So what?
那又怎样？
You can use that.
你可以拿去用
Use it for what?
用来干嘛？
For an advertisement or something. I don't know, you're the business guy.
拿去当宣传素材 我哪知道 我又不是生意人
I'm being rude. This is my associate, Béla Kletzki.
刚才有点失礼 这位是我搭档贝拉·克莱茨基
Nice to meet you, sir.
幸会 先生
I assume you're a table tennis player also?
你也是打桌球的？
I am. I am. Actually, I was the World Champion from '35 to '39.
是的 没错 我是1935到39年的世界冠军
He was the World Champion. I beat him today.
前世界冠军 我今天把他打败了
He beat me. But he's much younger than me.
他赢了我 他比我年轻得多
I'm much better than him, much more talented.
也强得多 更有天赋
I can't help but notice this tattoo. You were in one of the camps, weren't you?
我看到这个纹身 你是不是进过集中营？
Auschwitz-Birkenau. Yeah. Why do you ask?
奥斯威辛二号营区 没错 怎么问这个？
My son lost his life liberating you.
我儿子为了解放你们付出了生命
I'm sorry for your loss.
我深表遗憾
I thought you were liberated by the Soviets.
我还以为是苏联人解放你们的
- We were. It's Soviets. - It wasn't the Americans.
- 确实是 是苏联 - 并不是美国人
I didn't mean it literally. He was serving in the South Pacific.
不是字面意思 我儿子在太平洋战场
Well, what happened to him?
那他后来怎么了？
What do you mean? He was killed.
还能怎么了 他被杀了
You find that funny?
你觉得这好笑吗？
Oh, God. No, I just get nervous laughter sometimes.
天呐 不是 我有时一紧张就会笑
If it's any consolation,
说句安慰话
I'll be dropping a third atom bomb on their heads tomorrow.
我明天会送给他们第三颗原子弹
Yeah, I'm sure his mother's gonna get a lot of comfort
你这套安慰话 顶多忽悠你妈
that you're playing ping pong in his honor.
让她不反对你去打小乒乓
It's not that big of a deal, but I appreciate it.
感谢您操心我家事
Tell him-- He used to diffuse bombs for the Nazis.
跟他讲讲...他以前给纳粹拆弹
Tell him the story you told me about--
跟他讲讲那故事
- I've got a whole table of people waiting. - No, no, no, wait, wait.
- 我那桌还有人等我 我得走了 - 别走 别走
You're gonna love this story. Tell him.
他会喜欢的 讲给他听
- You wanna hear it? - Not really, but go ahead.
- 你想听吗？ - 不太想 但快说吧
No, tell him. It's beautiful.
别停 快说 是好故事
Okay, I'll make it quick. So...
行 那我长话短说
when I first got to the camp, I was put into housing.
我进集中营被分配住处的时候
Lucky for me, there was an officer who recognized me.
幸好有个军官认出我
He had seen me in 1935 at the World Championships in Prague.
他在1935年布拉格世锦赛上见过我
This guy was a real fan. I mean, a real fan, okay?
那人是真心崇拜我 真心的
You're telling me he let you live because you played ping pong?
他居然因为你会打小乒乓就让你活着？
They respected my skills, yeah.
他们很佩服我的本事 没错
So then, they taught me how to dismantle SC bombs.
于是他们教我拆圆柱高爆炸弹
Okay?
明白吗？
Each morning, they would send me into the woods with the bombs
每天早上他们把我和炸弹送到营外的树林里
on the outskirts of the camp where I could only do damage to myself.
就算炸了也伤不到别人
So one time,
有一回
I followed a honeybee.
我尾随一只蜜蜂
A bee?
什么蜂？
A honeybee,
蜜蜂
all the way to its hive.
一路跟它到了蜂巢
And I smoked all the bees out.
然后我用烟把蜜蜂全都熏跑
And then broke it open,
接着我把巢掰开
and I smeared the honey all over my chest, my arms, everywhere.
我把蜂蜜抹满全身 胸口 胳膊全抹上了
Why?
为什么？
'Cause later that night,
晚上回去后
I let all my bunk mates to lick the honey off of me for nourishment.
我就让室友把我身上的蜜舔掉充饥
（皇家套房）
Heads.
押正面
【抛硬币猜中者先选“发球”或“场地” 二选一】
- Fuck. - Endo, choice?
- 真倒霉 - 远藤 轮到你选了
（日语）发球
I'll go to that side.
我选那边
（决赛）
- On my right... - Come on, Marty! Come on!
- 右侧... - 加油 马蒂 加油
...Marty Mauser of the United States, ranked second,
是美国选手马蒂·毛瑟 世界排名第二
versus Koto Endo of Japan, unranked.
对阵日本选手远藤功人 未列排名
The gentlemen will battle to the best of five
比赛为五局三胜
in games to 21 points.
单局21分制
Each game shall be won by at least two points.
每局须至少领先两分才能取胜
Good luck, gentlemen.
祝二位好运
（第一局）
Quiet, please.
请保持安静
All right!
比赛开始
Point, Endo. One-nil.
远藤 得分 1比0
Come on, America!
加油 美国人
Point, Endo. Two-nil.
远藤 得分 2比0
All right, Marty!
加油 马蒂
Come on, Marty!
加油啊 马蒂
Point, Endo. Three-nil.
远藤 得分 3比0
Point, Endo. Four-nil.
远藤 得分 4比0
Come on, Marty!
加油 马蒂
Point, Endo. Five-nil.
远藤 得分 5比0
Service switches to Mauser.
换马蒂·毛瑟发球
（局分:美国8比日本19 场分:美国零比一）
Point, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
（局分:美国9比日本19 场分:美国零比一）
Nine serving 19.
9比19 美方发球
（第二局）
Point, Mauser. 10-19.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分 10比19
Okay, Marty!
好样的 马蒂
Point, Endo. 20-10.
远藤 得分 20比10
【局点:率先达到者只需再得一分即可赢此局】
Game point.
局点
Go! Serve.
快发球
Point, Endo. 21-10.
远藤 得分 21比10
Game, Endo.
本局远藤胜
Endo leads two games to zero.
远藤以两局比零领先
（局分:美国16比日本18 场分:美国零比二）
Point, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Eighteen-16.
18比16
(第三局)
Point, Mauser. 17-18.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分 17比18
Go, Marty! Come on!
加油 马蒂 加油
Service switches to Mauser.
换马蒂·毛瑟发球
Fuck.
该死
Point, Endo. 17-19.
远藤 得分 17比19
Oh, fuck.
真见鬼了
Point, Endo. 17-20.
远藤 得分 17比20
And match point.
赛点
Quiet, please.
请安静
Quiet. Settle down.
请坐好 保持安静
Your service, Mauser.
马蒂·毛瑟发球
Come on, Marty!
加油啊 马蒂
Fuck.
完了
No, bullshit! No!
不行 这是胡闹 不行
I want a rematch right now with a standard-league hard-bat!
现在就给我重赛 用正规硬拍
【1952年孟买世锦赛 日本选手佐藤博治首次用海绵拍 并赢得男单冠军】
That is unacceptable!
这太不像话了
What if I had a mechanical arm?
要是我装了机械臂呢？
What if I put glue on the ball? Would that be kosher?
要是我在球上涂胶水呢？这合规吗？
Why, he was getting coached the entire time! That is unacceptable!
他全场都被教练指点 这太不像话
I play real table tennis! Real table tennis!
我打的可是正经桌球 正经桌球
Unbelievable.
胡闹啊
...British Open champion from Japan...
本届英国公开赛冠军是...
Fuck you!
去死吧你
...Koto Endo!
...日本选手远藤功人
（日本新闻）
（特别报道）
（日语）第19届英国桌球公开赛上 日本首次问鼎冠军
（日语）这是自太平洋战争结束以来
（日语）首位日本选手在国际赛场上夺得胜利
（日语）获胜者为远藤功人
（日语）这位无名的日本挑战者 他在决赛中
（日语）以3比0的压倒性优势击败夺冠热门的美国强手
（日语）东京十万民众涌上街头
（日语）宛若庆典游行
（日语）热烈欢庆他的凯旋
（日语）远藤却以谦逊自持 愿以一名普通工匠身份回国
（日语）而非受封为所谓英雄
（日语）远藤16岁遭遇东京大轰炸 失去听觉
（日语）他在无声之中磨砺感官 最终以钢铁般意志征服赛场
（日语）如今 世界桌球的目光聚焦于我邦
（第23界世界桌球锦标赛）
（日语）本年度世界锦标赛主办地已定为东京
（日语）美国选手必将卷土重来 誓要洗刷败绩
（日语）但远藤并非孤军奋战
（日语）他背靠的是与他一道齐心实现民族愿望
（日语）共怀不屈精神的八千四百万同胞
（完）
（法国 巴黎）
Bonjour monsieur, Est‑ce que je peux vous aider?
（法语）您好先生 有什么需要吗？
Do you have a Milton Rockwell reservation?
米尔顿·罗克韦尔订的桌子在哪儿？
- Excusez-moi? - Milton Rockwell reservation, please.
- （法语）您说什么？ - 请查下米尔顿·罗克韦尔的订位
Ah, Rockwell?
（法语）您是说罗克韦尔吧？
So, listen, Marty, I wanna personally thank you
听着 马蒂 我得亲自谢谢你
for introducing me to table tennis.
谢谢你带我接触桌球
I had no idea what a phenomenon it was in the Asias.
我压根儿没想到 这玩意能在亚洲火成那样
- Oh, yeah. I know. - And how big it is in Japan!
- 哦 对 对 - 尤其在日本
That's what I was trying to tell you. It's huge.
我早跟你说了 火得很
So, I'm thinking of incorporating it into some of the promotional events
所以 我打算把桌球列进
we're gonna be doing over there in the fall.
秋季在那边的宣传项目里
How so? What are you thinking?
你准备怎么安排？
What I wanna do is stage an exhibition match
我想在世锦赛期间
around the time of the World Championships between you and Endo.
安排一场你和远藤的表演赛
- Mmm. - I think you'd like that idea.
- 嗯 - 你肯定会喜欢的
So I'm gonna make you an offer.
我给你开个价
I'll pay you a thousand dollars.
1000美金酬劳
【约1.2万美元 8.5万人民币 37万新台币】
I'll put you up at the Imperial Hotel in Tokyo.
还安排你住东京帝国饭店
【东京帝国饭店:建于19世纪末 东京三大顶级酒店之一】
And if you're leaving from New York, I'll give you a seat on my private plane,
要是你从纽约出发 还可以坐我的私人飞机
and you'll fly in luxury for the first time in your life.
让你这辈子体验一回什么叫奢华
Okay, we can negotiate my price later.
钱的事之后再商量
But this would be before or after the tournament?
但这安排是在赛前还是赛后？
- About a week before the event. - No, it's gotta be after.
- 赛前一周左右 - 不行 必须是赛后
I can't face off against the guy in public before it actually counts.
我不能在紧要关头前陪他演戏
Drama is very important to me. I can't undercut the drama.
好戏要留到关键时候
Let's not get tied up in minutiae.
先别纠结细节
- I just want to find out if you're interested in participating. - Yes.
- 我只是想知道你有没有兴趣参加 - 有啊
Oh, yeah. Of course. I'm interested in any opportunity to show off my talents.
当然有 凡是能让我露一手的机会我都不会错过
And you don't have to worry either, 'cause this time I'm gonna obliterate him.
别担心 这回我一定完胜他
It's really the racket that I'm playing,
主要是球拍的问题
but I can assure you, it's gonna be a victory.
但我保证 准能赢
Okay, listen. I need you to understand what this thing's about.
行了 听着 你得明白这是怎么回事
This is not an official match.
这不是正式比赛
It's not even a real game.
连真打都算不上
This is purely promotional, to entertain the Japanese people,
这是纯粹的宣传 目的就是讨好日本人
so they buy more of my pens, okay?
好让他们多买我的笔 明白吗？
You're gonna play a few games. You're gonna be great.
你上去打几局 你会很亮眼
- But you can't play better than Endo. - You want me to lose?
- 但别把远藤的风头给抢了 - 你让我故意输给他？
Marty, let me show you something.
马蒂 给你看样东西
Biggest magazine in Japan.
日本头号杂志
You made Endo a national treasure.
你把远藤捧成了国民英雄
- Listen-- - Why are you showing me this?
- 听着... - 你什么意思？
Do you think this makes me wanna lose? This makes me wanna win.
你觉得这会让我甘心输掉？我只会更想赢
Sometimes, when you lose you're a winner.
你要以退为进
- Let me explain. Let me explain. - I'm ten trillion times better than Endo.
- 听我解释一下 - 我比远藤强上万倍
You understand that, right? It's the racket that beat me.
打败我的不是人 而是那把球拍
- He's a mediocre player. - I couldn't care less.
- 他水平很一般 - 我不在乎
I don't care about table tennis. This is theater.
我根本不在乎桌球 这都不算体育
- What are you worried about? - My reputation.
- 你担心什么？ - 我的名声
- Your reputation? - Yes, my reputation.
- 你的名声？ - 没错 我的名声
I don't wanna throw my reputation in the trash for you. I'm not doing it.
我不会为你糟蹋我的名声 没门
Aren't you playing in a vaudeville circus act right now?
你现在不就在当小丑吗？
What do you mean, vaudeville? Finish that sentence.
什么小丑？把话说清楚
- What are you implying? - You're the halftime show, Marty.
- 你什么意思？ - 你不过是人家中场休息时的把戏
Of the Harlem Globetrotters! The finest athletes on the planet.
那可是哈林篮球队 都是世上最顶尖的运动员
I've probably played in front of 80,000 people since January.
从一月到现在 至少有八万观众看过我的表演
That's funny to you?
这好笑吗？
No. You're funny to me.
不是 你很可笑
I'm funny to you? You know what's funny to me?
我可笑？你知道什么最可笑吗？
That you want to entertain the Japanese so badly,
你这么低三下四去讨好日本人
and they murdered your son. That's funny to me.
而他们杀了你儿子 这才叫可笑
Look, you struck a nerve, I struck a nerve. Okay? Now we're even.
听着 咱俩互揭伤疤 扯平了 行吗？
Get out.
滚出去
Nah, I think you owe me a meal first.
不行 你还欠我一顿饭
（有请:哈林篮球队）
（塞克语）让我们热烈欢迎小乒乓登场
（塞克语）他们将上演“一闪一闪亮晶晶”
（南斯拉夫 萨拉热窝）
♪ And everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终将长大 ♪
（希腊 雅典）
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
（摩洛哥北部 丹吉尔）
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
Yeah, Coach, yeah!
快来 教练
（埃及 开罗）
Three, two, one. Say cheese.
三 二 一 说茄子
Cheese!
茄子
（西德 慕尼黑）
（比利时 布鲁塞尔）
（法语）接下来毛瑟 对阵 海豹
♪ 'Cause everybody's Gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终将长大 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
【1950年代种族隔离限制黑人入NBA 许多顶级球员改入表演球队】
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
（美国 纽约）
Excuse me.
借过
Hello.
也不打招呼
Please don't eat or drink in my room. It attracts bugs.
别在我房间吃喝 会生虫子
I just go in there to clean. That's it.
我只是进去打扫卫生 别多想
Well, you don't seem happy to see me.
见到我你一点都不高兴啊
Yeah, and you don't seem happy to see me.
是啊 你不也不高兴吗
So, now are you going to be staying here?
要留这儿住吗？
What, is that not okay?
怎么 不行吗？
Don't worry. I'll be out of your hair in a few weeks.
别担心 我过几周就走 不烦你
Don't be stupid.
懂点事吧
- Why? What's in a few weeks? - World Championship.
- 走去哪儿？过几周有什么事？ - 世锦赛
- So, where's that gonna be? - Tokyo.
- 在哪儿办？ - 东京
Tokyo, Japan?
日本的东京？
Are you asking me if Tokyo's in Japan?
还有其他东京吗？
Is that a serious question?
你没正经问题吗？
You look very tired to me.
你看起来累坏了
Yeah, 'cause I just traveled halfway around the world. I'm tired.
是啊 我刚跑了大半个地球 能不累吗
I was busy. I was working. I was making money.
我很忙 忙着工作 忙着挣钱
You know, while everybody is at work in the building,
趁着这会儿楼里没人用热水
it would be a good time for you to take a nice, long, hot shower.
去好好洗个热水澡吧
- Here. - What's this?
- 给你 - 这是什么？
I got you something.
专门带给你的
It's from an original Egyptian pyramid.
这可是从真金字塔上敲下来的
We built that.
还记得小时候吗？
Okay.
嗯
Hey, Levi. You got a lot taller.
嘿 利维 又长高了
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, you did.
- 我没有 - 有啊
- Excuse me. Can I help you? - Yeah. Let's go.
- 你是哪位 有事吗？ - 有 跟我走
- Come on, come on. - Hey! What are you doing?
- 走 赶紧的 - 你干嘛？
- Let's go, let's go. Let's go. - No! What the fuck are you doing?
- 跟我走 快走 - 不 你搞什么鬼？
- You're under arrest. - No, I'm not!
- 你被捕了 - 我没有
- Yes, you are. Come here. Stop moving! - What am I under arrest for?
- 被捕了 过来 别乱动 - 凭什么逮捕我？
- That's my toiletries! Ow! - You're under arrest.
- 那是我的洗漱用品 哎呦 - 你被捕了
- For what? - Armed robbery. Come on.
- 犯了什么事？ - 持械抢劫 走吧
Armed rob-- What are you talking about?
持械？你胡说什么呢？
You're gonna hurt yourself if you keep moving!
不想受伤就别动了
- What is going on? - Come on.
- 到底怎么回事？ - 走
- Murray, where's my mother? Murray. - I asked her to leave for a bit.
- 老默 我妈在哪？ - 我叫她先走开一下
You told her-- What the fuck is going on? I'm getting arrested! Help me!
你什么？到底搞什么鬼？抓我？帮帮我！
Sal, Sal. I wanna talk to him in private. Excuse us. Just go.
萨尔 萨尔 我跟他单独谈谈 你先回避下
- What do you want me to do? - Sal? You know this guy?
- 去哪儿？ - 萨尔？ 你认识这人？
- Just go in the back for a while. - Yeah.
- 先去屋里待会儿 - 好
Close the door.
关上门
All right, if it gets crazy just holler.
行 情况不对就喊我
What the fuck is going on, Murray? That money I took, you owed me.
搞什么鬼 我拿的那钱是你欠我的
No, no, no, no. It was money you stole at gunpoint.
不 别胡扯 那钱是你持枪抢的
- No, you promised me... Excuse me. - No, you didn't...
- 不 你答应过我的 听我说 - 不 你根本没...
That was my money and you took--
那钱本来就该给我的
You promised me that money. I'm not... Why would I make this up?
你答应过要给我的 我没胡扯
- It was money for my trip to England. - What happened on your trip?
- 那是去英国的路费 - 哦 比赛怎么样？
What do you mean, what happened on my trip?
你什么意思？
- You lost! - No, I didn't!
- 你输了 - 我没输
- You did! - Where did you hear that?
- 你就是输了 - 听谁说的？
- No, I got cheated against. - Do you know how many times
- 不 对手作弊了 - 你知不知道我多少次
- in the middle of the night... - No, no. Stop with that.
- 半夜得替你... - 行了 别扯了
- Shut up and listen to me! - Don't lecture me.
- 闭嘴 好好听着 - 少教训我
Shut up!
闭嘴
You don't know how many times I had to get woken up
你不知道我多少次半夜被叫醒
- and bail you out. - When did I ask you to do that?
- 替你擦屁股 - 谁让你管的？
- When have I ever asked for your help? - You never asked me to do that.
- 我求过你吗？ - 你确实没求过我
- Exactly! - But I did.
- 没错 - 但我还是帮了
And now, you're gonna be a big boy.
你都多大了 你该懂事了
- It's your turn. - A big boy?
- 你得成器了 - 成器？
- Did you really just say that to me? - Yeah. Yeah, you know, look...
- 你竟然教育我？ - 没错 听好了
I can't support your mother for the rest of my life.
我不能永远供着你妈
- You're not gonna have to. - Oh, yeah? Why not?
- 谁让你操心了 - 哦 那谁操心？
- Because I'm gonna step up. - You're gonna step up? How?
- 我来承担 - 你承担？怎么承担？
In a way you can't imagine. She's gonna be living on Fifth Avenue
我会让我妈妈荣华富贵
in an apartment and building with a elevator,
住进有电梯的豪宅
and a man who works in the elevator that takes her every time she needs to use it.
还有门童 还有专人伺候
Sure, sure, sure. All right, look.
得了得了 听好了
I'm gonna give you two options, okay?
我给你两个选择 你自己选
I think you'll like the first one.
你应该能接受第一个
You come back to the shop.
回鞋店干活
This time, no more bullshit.
这回别再不务正业了
None of this ping-pong mishegoss, okay?
别再耍你那小乒乓了 明白吗？
I'm gonna give you much more responsibility,
我会给你更大的权责
because truth be told, you're an amazing salesman.
说实话 你卖鞋挺有一手的
I could sell shoes to an amputee.
是啊 我都能卖鞋给蛇
So what? What's the other option?
那又怎样 我偏不干 第二个选择呢？
- I press charges. - You're not doing that.
- 那我就控告你 - 你才不会
- Lloyd is a witness... - You're not doing that.
- 洛伊是证人... - 你不会那么干的
...and you go to jail!
...然后你去蹲大牢
Really? You'd do that to your own kin? Are you out of your mind?
真的？对你亲外甥这么狠？你疯了吗？
- We'll see... You took it upon yourself. - Hey, Sal! Sal!
- 得让你尝尝教训 - 萨尔 出来 萨尔
- What? - How much is he paying you right now?
- 干嘛？ - 他给你多少钱来吓我？
What are you talking about, paying me?
胡说什么 什么钱？
How much is my uncle paying for you to scare me?
我舅给你多少钱来吓我？
'Cause whatever it is, I'll double it for you to suck my dick.
不管多少 我出双倍 快来跪下给我舔吧
- What? - Suck my dick.
- 什么？ - 给我舔
- You have terrible breath. - Watch your mouth, you--
- 你口臭真难闻 - 嘴放干净点 你这...
- Ow! Fuck! - Let's go. We're going now.
- 噢 该死 - 走 现在就走
- He just hit me! - Stop. Please stop.
- 他刚打了我 - 住手 行了行了
- Murray, he hit me. - Stop.
- 老默 他打我 - 停下
We worked everything out.
我们都商量好了
You were in the other room. You didn't hear. We already worked it out.
听见没 我们商量好了
- He's paying back everything. - Animal.
- 他会补偿一切 - 粗鲁
He gave me the money, and everything's okay.
他把钱给我了 都没事了
- Where did you get that? - I got it from your luggage.
- 你从哪儿拿的钱？ - 你行李箱里
Are you out of your mind? That's my money for Japan!
你疯了吗 那是我去日本的钱
- Are you out of your fucking mind? - Let's go. Let's go.
- 你是不是傻了？ - 走 赶紧走
Just take him downtown, damn it! Take him downtown!
押到局里 把他押走
- Okay. All right! Okay! I'll stop! - You're done. You're done.
- 好 好 我听你的 停下 - 你玩完了 彻底完了
- Please. Stop. Stop. - Let's go.
- 拜托 停下 停下 - 跟我走
- All right. Let him go. Let him go. - Let him go?
- 好 放开他 放开他 - 放开他？
- Let him go. Let him go. - Sit up.
- 放开他 放开他 - 坐好
Listen, apologize.
听着 道个歉
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
行 对不起 我错了
Take his cuffs off.
给他解开手铐
- This is what's gonna happen, okay? - Okay.
- 接下来这样安排 听好 - 好
We're gonna meet your mom at the Garden Café.
咱们去花园咖啡馆见你妈
We're gonna have a really nice dinner.
咱们好好吃顿饭
And let's just put all this shit behind us, okay?
之前的破事儿就翻篇了 行吗？
Okay. All right.
行 没问题
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - You're sorry?
- 我错了 我错了 真错了 - 你知错了？
We'll take care of everything. Just get dressed.
剩下的事慢慢解决 赶紧穿衣服
- Come on. I love you. - All right. I love you too.
- 好了 舅舅爱你 - 行 我也爱你
Your nephew's a piece of shit, you know that?
你外甥真是个废物
Oh, Jesus. I'm so sorry.
哎 天呐 实在对不住
Here another ten.
再给你十块
Yeah, all right.
好 行吧
Garden Café, huh? What do you get?
花园咖啡馆啊 点什么馅三明治？
The pastrami, what else?
烟熏肉啊 还能什么？
【烟熏肉三明治:东欧犹太移民特色食物】
- Ah, pastrami. - What do you get?
- 噢 烟熏肉 - 你点什么馅？
Roast beef.
英式烤牛肉
【英式烧牛肉:传统英式料理】
- Roast beef? - Yeah.
- 英式烧牛肉？ - 嗯
Goyishecop!
（意第绪语）你这吃洋饭的条子
Hey.
嘿
Open up. Come on.
开门 别磨蹭
- Break it down. - Break it in?
- 把门撞开 - 你确定？
Fuck!
见鬼
Hey! Where you going?
嘿 你往哪儿跑？
Shit.
糟了
- What happened? - He went out the window.
- 怎么回事？ - 他从窗户跑了
- What? Wait! - Frankie!
- 什么？怎么回事？ - 弗兰基
- What? - He's coming down the escape right now.
- 怎么了？ - 他沿着消防梯下去了
There he goes! Down the escape!
就在那儿 别让他跑了
- Oh, shit. - Go, go, go!
- 该死 - 快追 快追 快追
（纽约警察）
（埃塞克斯街宠物店）
- You hold it. - I'm just gonna use the phone in the back.
- 来 摸摸它 - 我去后头打个电话
See how much he likes you?
这兔子多喜欢你啊
- Hello? - Hey, Wally. How you doing? It's Marty.
- 喂 - 嘿 沃利 最近怎样 我是马蒂
- Are you working tonight? - Of course I'm working.
- 今晚出车吗？ - 废话 当然出
Okay, great. Bring your cab and as much cash as you can.
行 好 开着车 多带现金
I want you to meet me at The Halsey on 28th Street, okay?
到28街的哈尔西碰头 明白吗？
What? You wanna go hustling again?
什么？你又想去骗局子？
Yeah, exactly.
对 没错
No, no, no. I got my ass kicked last time.
不 不 不 还记得上次多惨吗？
We went all the way to Staten Island,
咱们跑去史坦顿岛
and within ten minutes, they recognized you, and now you want to go back?
十分钟你就被认出了 你还想回去？
No, It's fine. We're gonna go to that place that Quinn was talking about in Jersey.
不去 这次去新泽西那边 奎因提过的那个地方
That's a bad idea.
坏主意
- That's your new pet. - No, Mom, I want the armadillo.
- 这就是你的新宠物了 - 不 妈妈 我想要个犰狳
No, I already--
我们商量过...
You know what? I'm just gonna get you the armadillo.
这样吧 我给你拿个犰狳
I'm gonna give him to you, and then you can make a decision. Okay?
你抱好 你自己挑
They're not reptiles. They're mammals.
这也是哺乳动物啊
Okay, great. You're a beautiful man. I'll see you in an hour and a half.
行 太好了 你真是个大好人 一个半小时后见
- Where? - At the Halsey. Okay. I love you.
- 哪儿？ - 哈尔西见 就这样 好哥们
Thank you. Bye.
谢了 再见
Okay, good. Here you are.
很好 你来了
Is there a way I can go out the back or something, please?
有没有后门可以出去？
What? Why are you looking at me like that?
干嘛 你那眼神啥意思？
Aren't you gonna say something to me?
你不打算说点什么吗？
What, congratulations?
哦 恭喜是吧？
- Congratulations? - Yes.
- 恭喜？ - 对
- Are you kidding me? - What do you want me to say?
- 你傻吗？ - 你想让我说什么？
I've been trying to get in contact with you for eight months.
这八个月我一直在找你
Okay, I see what you're trying to do. It's not gonna work.
行了 这招没用的
- Excuse me? - That's not mine.
- 什么意思？ - 那孩子跟我没关系
- It is absolutely yours. - No, it's not. I pull out.
- 绝对是你的 - 不可能 我都拔出来了
- Yes it is. - Does Ira pull out?
- 就是你的 - 你丈夫艾勒也拔出来吗？
- What do you want me to say to that? - It's a simple question.
- 你要我怎么说？ - 如实回答
Does he pull out when he has sex with you?
他和你上床时会拔出来吗？
- Answer it. - You want me to answer that?
- 回答我 - 你竟然要我答这个？
Yes! Answer it. Does he pull out when he...
对 快回答 他拔不拔出来
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起 不哭 不哭
I'm a mess right now. I'm really a mess, Rachel.
我陷入麻烦了 瑞秋 到处麻烦缠身
I lost in London, by the way--
我在伦敦输了后...
Hey!
嘿
God.
见鬼
What's this?
你们干嘛呢？
His father died.
他爸爸过世了
- Bullshit! - This is my friend since I was eight.
- 放屁 - 她是我从八岁起的朋友
Am I talking to you?
我问你了吗？
Ira, I've known her since I was eight years old.
艾勒 我从八岁就认识她了
My father just died. She was consoling me.
我爸刚走 她在安慰我
Honey, it's okay.
亲爱的 没事的
- Shut up! Don't touch me! - That's how you talk to your wife?
- 闭嘴 别碰我 - 你跟老婆就这样说话吗？
Yeah, that's how I talk to her.
对 有意见吗？
- Okay. - Huh?
- 行 - 有意见吗？
No, no, no! Come on. Keep going.
来 来 来 把意见大声说出来
- Keep going. - Marty, just stop.
- 说出来 - 马蒂 别说了
I'll rip that unibrow right off his fucking forehead!
看我不撕烂你的臭脸
You wanna get physical? Like an ape?
你想动手吗？跟个禽兽一样？
Ira.
艾勒
Ira! Come back inside. What are you doing?
艾勒 回来 快进来 你要干嘛？
Somebody get the fucking cops over here, huh?
谁去把条子叫来 快点
- What did you do? - Fuck! I gotta get out of here.
- 你要干嘛？ - 该死 我得赶紧溜
Why are you running from the cops?
为什么要躲警察
Come on, he's right here!
他就在这儿 快去抓
There's no way out the back?
有后门吗？
- What? What-- - Please! Come on. Rachel! Focus.
- 后什么？ - 瑞秋 专心点 有没有？
It leads out the back. Go.
从这出去 走吧
Okay. Okay. Thank you, thank you.
行 行 谢谢 谢谢
- Where do we meet? Where? - I'll tell you later. I'll tell you later.
- 别走 我上哪找你？ - 回头再说 回头再说
Guys, you see a white kid with glasses come through here?
有没有看到一个戴眼镜的白小子从这儿出来？
Nobody saw him?
没人看见？
No English, huh?
听不懂英语？
Please insert a nickel if you'd like to continue the conversation.
如需继续通话 请投币五分
A nickel? They're gonna cut us off.
要五分？电话要断了
- Do you have a nickel? - No.
- 你有五分吗？ - 没
Mom, I'm not lying. I promise you this will be the last time.
妈 真没骗你 我保证这次是最后一次了
Are my eyes broke, or is that motherfucking Mouse?
难道我眼花了 这不是我的小毛毛吗？
- Thank you. - What's up, baby?
- 谢谢 - 近来怎样？
Thank you so much. I really appreciate it. Thank you.
太谢谢了 你要帮大忙了 谢谢
- You smell like a fish, Marty. - I know, that's why
- 你一身臭味 - 我知道
we gotta get a hotel room. I need to get a shower.
所以咱们得开个房 我得洗个澡
How you doing? Hey, can we get a hotel room, please?
你好 麻烦开一间房
- Four dollars. - You said it was three dollars.
- 四块 - 你刚还说三块呢
- That was for the last room. It's four. - Why is it four dollars now?
- 那是刚才那间价格 现在四块 - 怎么现在变四块了？
Let me get four bucks. I'll pay you back, I promise.
先借我四块 我保证还你
I'm telling you right now, we only got ten to play with.
我跟你说 我们只有十块本钱可以赌
【10美元 约120美元 820人民币 3,750新台币】
You brought ten dollars? What's wrong with you?
就带了十块？搞什么鬼？
- You gave me a hour notice. - How are we supposed to make money?
- 你一小时前才通知我 - 那咱们怎么赢钱？
Nigger, I got kids! I'm a fucking taxi driver.
老兄 我得养娃呢 我就是个开出租的
Do you have a cheaper room? It doesn't have to be nice.
有便宜点的房吗？不用讲究
There's a room on the fifth floor, but you can't use the shower.
五楼还有间 但不准洗澡
- Okay, how much is that? - Two fifty.
- 那好 多少钱？ - 两块五
【2.5美元 约30美元 210人民币 960新台币】
- Let me get three dollars. Thank you. - You better pay me back.
- 借我三块 谢谢 - 别赖账
- Yeah, I will I will. - You lucky I love you.
- 放心 放心 - 多亏你还有我这个哥们
- Jimmy. Jimmy. - It's coming out your winnings.
- 吉米 吉米 - 待会从赢的钱里扣
Give me the keys.
把钥匙递来
What's that smell?
这啥味儿？
Oh, my God! Fuck.
哎呦 我去
- Wow! What is that? - Oh, my God!
- 我去 怎么那么臭 - 天呐
He had a little accident.
出了点小意外
God! He had an enormous accident.
这哪是小意外啊
That's horrible.
难闻死了
- Smells like shit! - Fuck!
- 跟掉粪坑里一样 - 我去
Jimmy, you smell like shit.
吉米 你才掉进过粪坑
- Is that your breath or the dog? - Can I get my key, please?
- 你嘴比你那狗还臭 - 能把钥匙给我了吗？
Do not go in the elevator with that dog. Take the stairs.
不许带那狗上电梯 走楼梯
- Are you kidding me? - Wash that dog.
- 别闹 - 赶紧洗狗
Goodbye, Jimmy.
晚安 吉米
- How big is she, Marty? - Very big. Big.
- 她肚子有多大了 - 非常大 大得吓人
Is she popping out tomorrow?
大到明天就生吗？
I don't know when she's popping out. Look, all I know is it's not mine.
我哪知道什么时候生 我只知道孩子不是我的
She has an agenda. You don't know her like I do.
我太了解她了 她有她的小算盘
She's stuck in a miserable marriage. She has a horrible life.
她婚姻不幸 生活惨淡
She's trying to pin it down on me.
她想借我逃避
Since we were eight years old, she's trying to get me stuck.
从八岁起 她就想把我套牢
- Your bummy ass? - Yes.
- 套你这穷光蛋？ - 没错
Yeah, she is crazy.
那她真有毛病
It's a biological impossibility that that kid is mine, okay?
从生理上讲那孩子绝不可能是我的
- So, you using raincoats? - No, I don't need to.
- 你戴套了？ - 没 我不需要
So you must be shooting blanks.
那你多半是废了
Do you know what continence is, Wally? No?
你知道“定海锁脉功”吗？
Every time I take a piss, I pull back,
每次尿一半我就憋着
I hold my urine in, and I count to ten Mississippi.
然后默唱首生日歌
- That's how you build up the muscle. - Oh, my God!
- 专练那块肌肉 - 我去
That's how you get a fuckin' bladder infection.
你这是专练膀胱炎的
What are you doing? That's my mail.
你干嘛呢？那是我的信
Are you out of your mind?
瞎看什么
You need to grab them goddamn diapers.
我看你得用尿布了
No.
不用
And get a fucking grip.
你得理智点
I'm not a father.
我才不当什么爹
（国际乒联）
- Yo, Marty. - What?
- 哟 马蒂 - 干嘛？
What's the Ritz?
丽兹酒店是哪出？
Why?
干嘛问这个？
You got a $1,500 fine
你被国际乒联
from the International Table Tennis...
罚了1500美金
【约1.2万美元 8.5万人民币 37万新台币】
- What? - ...Association and...
- 什么？ - ...他们说...
- And they... - Bring it in here!
- 他们还... - 快拿给我
- And they banned your scrawny ass. - Give me that.
- 他们还把你给禁赛了 - 给我
- Are you okay? - Who the fuck are you?
- 你没事吧？ - 你他妈从哪冒出来的？
God! Help me! Get this fucking thing off of me!
快来帮我 快抬起来
My dog!
我的狗
- Holy shit! - Shit! What happened?
- 天呐 - 见鬼 出啥事了
Come on! Get outta that fuckin' tub and help me!
快点 从浴缸滚出来帮我
My dog's drowning, man. Come on! Help me!
我狗要淹死了 赶紧 帮我
Okay, I'm flipping it. Take your arm out.
好 我要抬了 准备抽手
- One. Two. - Lift it off!
- 一 二 - 快抬
Three.
三
- Take your arm out! - Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- 快把手抽出来 - 疼死了 疼死了
Fuck! Fuck!
操 操
Oh, fuck, your arm.
哎呦 你的胳膊
Lean back. Lean back. Don't look at it.
坐好 坐好 别看伤口
- I need to make a tourniquet. - Oh, fuck!
- 我得弄个止血带 - 噢 操
- Come here. Give me your arm. - What are you doing?
- 过来 把手给我 - 你要干嘛？
- What are you doing? - Give me your arm.
- 要干嘛？ - 手给我
- Fuck. - Where's my dog?
- 该死 - 我的狗呢？
Don't worry about the dog! Give me your arm.
别管那狗了 手给我
- Moses. - Do nothing. Do nothing.
- 摩西 - 别乱动 别乱动
I got you. Don't worry.
有我在呢 别担心
Wally, call an ambulance!
沃利 快叫救护车
- Are you good? - No, I'm not good.
- 你还好吧？ - 不 我一点也不好
Where are my glasses?
我的眼镜呢？
I mean, are you hurt? You just fell through the floor.
我是说 你受伤没？你刚从楼板掉下去了
Fucking horseshit. I'm getting our money back.
真见鬼 我得把房钱要回来
Marty, we gotta get the fuck out of here.
马蒂 咱们闯大祸了 得赶紧溜
It's $2.50. What are you talking about?
才两块五 你别傻了
I'm asking for way more than $2.50. You see what just happened?
我要的可不止两块五 你没懂吗？
Wait here. Wait.
在这等着 等着
- For how long? - Ten seconds.
- 等多久? - 十秒钟
My shoes, my clothes.
我的鞋 我的衣服
Everything's soaking wet. It's a mess in there.
全湿透了 你们怎么搞的
- Why don't you put a sock in it? - You wanna switch?
- 闭嘴吧 - 你得感谢没砸到你屋
- Hey. - You! I... I told you not to use the fucking shower.
- 嘿 - 是你 我跟你说过不能洗澡
No, you didn't. You're the one that rented me the room, okay?
你才没说 是你把房租给我的 懂吗？
I could have broken my neck falling out of that ceiling.
我差点摔死
That can fucking still happen too.
再闹你现在也能死
- Are you threatening me right now? - Yeah. Yeah.
- 你在威胁我吗？ - 对 对
- Rellay? You want to threaten me? - Yeah.
- 居然敢威胁我？ - 对
- Basement is locked! - Who's got the fucking key?
- 地下室锁了 - 谁拿了钥匙？
Listen, man! Listen! I want my money for my room...
给我听好了 听好了 把房钱还给我
- Ambulance. - ...and I want a reimbursement
- 救护车来了 - ...我还要赔偿
- for my shit that got ruined. - Are you serious?
- 我的东西都毁了 - 你当真？
- Yes! - You're not gonna get your shit back.
- 废话 - 一分都不会给你
- $7.50! - You'll get nothing.
- 一共七块五 - 一分钱也不给
【约90美元 630人民币 2,900新台币】
- Come on. Help me! - Paramedics.
- 快点帮我 - 医护来了
- Good, you're here. - Where's the patient at?
- 你们可来了 - 病人在哪儿？
He's in here. It's his arm. He's lost a lot of blood.
就在那儿 手臂受伤了 流了好多血
What happened?
怎么回事?
- Bathtub fell on him. - Bathtub fell on him?
- 浴缸砸他身上了 - 浴缸砸他身上了？
I can't feel my arm.
我胳膊没知觉了
Yo, Jimmy. Come on, you gotta help me with this dog.
吉米 你得替我照看好摩西
- I don't got nobody free. - We gotta get him to the vet.
- 我这儿没人手 - 那就送他去兽医那儿
- I got nobody free right now. - He's my family, man.
- 真腾不出人手 - 他是我的家人
Listen, now. Just give me the $2.50, and I'll get outta here. Forget the $7.50.
听着 把两块五还我 我就走 七块五不要了
- Just give me $2.50. - I can't help you.
- 把两块五给我就行 - 我做不了主
See the owner tomorrow.
明天找老板要
- Kid. - It's your shitty ceiling
- 小子 - 都怪你的
- in this crummy hotel. - Kid. Oh!
- 烂地板 - 小子 小子
- I ain't giving you nothing. - What?
- 什么都不给 - 什么？
Kid. Come on. Just bring the dog to the vet.
小子 帮我把狗送到兽医那儿
I can't. I got work. I got a job.
不行 我得工作 有活要干
- I can't get fired. - You got a job?
- 我不能被开除 - 你有工作？
- I'll give you double what you're getting. - No, I can't. I can't.
- 我出双倍工钱 - 不 行不通 不行
I'll give you triple. Come on.
那就三倍 来吧
- Take it easy. Calm down. - Okay.
- 别乱动 别乱动 - 行吧
Okay, look in that bag. See the bag on the chair?
好 打开那个包 椅子上的包
Yeah, go in that bag, okay? Open it up.
对 把包打开
I'm gonna apply a tourniquet to you.
我得给你上个止血带
I'm gonna remove the other tourniquet right now.
换掉原来的
Take 50 for yourself. Yeah.
拿50给你自己
【约600美元 4,100人民币 1.8万新台币】
Bring 50 for the vet, okay?
再拿50给兽医 明白吗？
We got blood squirting out.
有血喷出来
He's on 13th and 1st.
兽医在13街和1大道交口
And tell him I'll be there as soon as I can get there, okay?
告诉他我一完事就赶过去 懂吗？
You're gonna give this motherfucker money?
你居然要给他钱？
He's the one who fuckin' dropped the tub on ya.
是这混蛋砸的你
I told him not to get in the fuckin' bath.
我警告过他别洗澡了
Fucking mensch, kid.
小子 你一看就靠谱
Stretcher ready? We'll take him to Bellevue.
准备抬 送他去贝尔维尤医院
Fucking mensch.
一看就靠谱
We can still turn around and take him to the vet.
现在掉头送他去兽医还来得及
No. No.
不用 不用
- Fifty dollars is more than enough. - You know what's better than 50? 100.
- 50块绰绰有余了 - 什么比50大？是100块
We can clean house with a hundred.
100本钱能让咱大赚一笔
Don't be greedy, you fucking Jew.
你个贪心的犹太鬼
- No, no. It's a $1,500 fine. You're the one that showed it to me. - Shut your mouth!
- 有1500美元罚款 你亲自拿给我的 别忘了 - 别叫了
- By the way, we gotta do this every night for two weeks, - "We"?
- 而且我们还得连赌两周夜场 - 我们？
- or else I can't go to Japan. - Oh, no, no, no.
- 否则我就去不了日本了 - 不 不 不
I'm not taking two weeks off work 'cause you fucked up.
我才不会因为你的错 为你耽误两周工作
Hey. Take this, boy. Take this.
来 吃点这个 吃点这个
There you go. Good boy.
吃吧 好孩子
Loosen up the collar on this motherfucker, man.
把这狗的项圈解开
- All right. - He sound like a radiator.
- 好 - 他都喘不过气了
We're gonna go play,
咱们先去赌
we'll drop him off at the vet on the way back.
回来顺路再送他去兽医
- What's a couple of hours to this guy? - Marty, I got rides set up, man.
- 这也就几个小时 - 马蒂 我有接送安排 别忘了
Huh. Moses.
叫摩西
Lane three. That's you.
到你了 三号球道
- Hi, how you doing? - Could I help?
- 你好 - 要点什么？
Can I get a lane?
还有球道吗？
Probably gonna be a half hour, 40 minutes.
大概得等三四十分钟样子
- That's okay. - You all right with that?
- 没问题 - 你确定能等？
- You want shoes? - I'll just grab 'em later.
- 现在拿鞋吗？ - 我待会儿再拿
Done. Over.
结束 输了
Fucking pathetic. Pay up.
弱得可怜 给钱
Who wants next?
谁来下一局？
Can I play? Hey! Can I play?
我来一局 嘿 怎么玩？
- It's a dollar a game. - Okay.
- 一块钱一局 - 行吧
- What's your name? - Seth.
- 你叫什么？ - 塞思
Let's get a warm-up rally going.
先来几回热热身吧
Nah. Put up or shut up. I don't play for free.
不行 要打就押钱 否则滚蛋 我不白陪打
All right. Never heard of that.
行吧 没听过这规矩
- I'm holding. - He's holding.
- 我管账 - 钱给他
You're holding? Why is he holding?
你管账？凭什么让他管？
- Have you got yours? - Can I trust you?
- 你带钱了吗？ - 不许耍赖
Trust me, you can.
相信我 没问题
- Where are we at? - All right, Seth vs. Roger.
- 这句谁对谁？ - 塞思对阵罗杰
Dollar game.
一块钱一局
【约12美元 85人民币 375新台币】
I serve.
我发球
What are you doing? I'm not even looking.
你干嘛呢？我还没准备好
- One-zip. - I wasn't even looking.
- 1比0 - 我刚才都没看
- No, you can't do that. - What?
- 不行 不能用手接球 - 什么？
You gotta let the ball hit the other side.
你要是接不到球
You can't catch it with your paddle. My point.
就得让球自己落地 我得分
- What are you talking about? - You can't do that.
- 你在扯什么？ - 手接球不算
You gotta let the ball fall off the table.
拍子接不住就得让球落地
- That's ridiculous. - You're cheating.
- 胡说八道 - 你犯规了
- I'm cheating? - Yeah, that's called cheating.
- 我犯规了？ - 对 这就叫犯规
- You're not following the rules. - Fine. Take the point.
- 你没按规矩来 - 行吧 分给你
- Thank you. Give me the ball. - One-one.
- 谢谢 把球给我 - 1比1
Fuck!
见鬼
- That was close. - That was good. That was good.
- 好险 - 打得好 打得好
Oh. No, no, no, no, no.
噢 不 不 不
No, no. Take it.
收着吧 收着吧
I should have spotted you, like, five points, man.
我本该让你五分的 伙计
You've had a rough enough day already. Keep it.
你今天够倒霉了 留着吧
Thank you, brother. Thank you.
谢谢 伙计 谢谢
It's all good.
没事儿
Good game.
打得不错
All right, Adam. Adam, let's go.
好了 亚当 亚当 该你了
- What do you want to put on? - I can go 50 cents.
- 你想押多少？ - 五毛
You got a ball?
你手里有球吗？
What happened to your nose?
你鼻子怎么回事？
I got one, I got one.
我有球 我有球
Fare ran out on me.
有人赖账跑了
Fare from what? What happened?
赖什么账？怎么回事？
I'm a taxi driver. From Manhattan.
我开出租的 曼哈顿来的
- Manhattan? - Yeah.
- 曼哈顿？ - 对
That's an expensive trip, man.
那路费可不便宜 伙计
Oh, yeah. $20, $25.
可不是 大概20块到25块呢
Well, the high rollers tip five,
碰上有钱的主儿
so that's five in tips. And...
还能再给5块小费
I fucking get to the spot, the guy chokes me out,
我刚把他送到 那人从后面掐住我脖子
- punching me in the back of the head. - No.
- 朝我后脑勺猛揍 - 不会吧
Takes my money and run the fuck off.
然后抢了钱就跑
Caught up to the motherfucker, and, boy...
后来我追上那混蛋 你猜怎么着
I beat the brights off that motherfucker, man.
我把他揍得眼冒金星
And I took what he had.
我把他搜刮了个遍
You took what he had?
你把他搜刮了？
Hell, yeah! You fucking damn right.
那当然 谁他妈的会放过
- You added that to your roll? - Sure did.
- 你把钱踹你兜里？ - 当然了
To that fat roll I've seen you pulling out.
就是那厚厚一大摞钞票
It's principle. It's fucking principle!
这是原则问题 他妈的原则
I understand that. I would keep it hidden.
我懂 但是建议你把钱藏好
I would keep that down, if I were you, in this place.
在这儿这种地方 最好别显摆
Not everybody's as nice as Christian is, I'm telling you.
可不是谁都像他那么面善
That's my point.
这分是我的
What about that asshole right there?
那打球的臭小子是谁？
I don't know who the fuck that guy is.
我哪知道那是谁
- You can't serve like that. - What do you mean?
- 你不能这么发球 - 为什么不能？
I've been serving like that for years.
我这么发球都好几年了
- Hey, Roger. Roger. Hello. - That's ridiculous.
- 嘿 罗杰 罗杰 给你说话呢 - 你们的规则真荒唐
- Give me one more minute. - Our lane is open.
- 再打一分钟 - 球道轮到我们了
- The lane can wait. It's fine. - No, we gotta go now.
- 回来再打保龄球 - 不行 现在就得去
- They're gonna give it away. - I'm playing now.
- 要不然就让给别人了 - 我正打乒乓呢
I have been waiting all night to bowl. Let's go. Come on.
为了打保龄球我都等一晚上了 赶紧的 快走
Roger.
罗杰
- My point. - Look what you made me do.
- 我得分 - 瞎喊什么的
I gotta go.
我不玩了
- What do you mean you gotta go? - Give me my dollar back.
- 什么意思？ - 把那一块钱还我
We're in the middle of a game.
比赛还没打完呢
You forfeit the game, then. Give me my dollar.
你走就算弃权 把我的钱也给我
- Give me my dollar back! - Relax. Back up, back up.
- 把我的钱也给我 - 别激动 退后点
- He's gonna leave the game? - You didn't finish the game.
- 他弃权了 - 打完再给
All right, then you play. Then you play.
行啊 那你接着打 你来打
I'm broke, man. I gave him my last ten.
我没钱了 最后十块都给他了
I'll play you.
我跟你打
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
喔 喔 喔
Oh, wow. I didn't know you guys played table tennis.
哇塞 你们这种人也会玩桌球了
Put up a dollar. Do you have a dollar?
一块一局 你玩得起吗？
- Fuck you. Put up five. - You don't have five dollars.
- 去你的 我押五块 - 你哪来的五块钱
【约60美元 400人民币 1,900新台币】
Oh, wow. You must have robbed someone.
哇塞 你肯定是抢来的吧
Put your money where your mouth is.
有种你也把钱亮出来
Why don't I put my penis where your mouth is?
不如我亮出家伙 教你做人
Red shirt, Wally and whatever the fuck his name is.
计分的 沃利对阵这个混蛋
Mark it blank, baby. I'll be right back.
先别计分 回来再打
Where are you going?
你去哪？
I will mark it blank!
那我先不计分
What's going on here?
看什么热闹呢？
The colored boy is about to lose all his money.
这黑小子要把钱输光了
Yeah, to this asshole right here.
是啊 都输给这混蛋了
- Fuck! - Match point.
- 该死 - 赛点
- Match point. Here we go. - Wally! Come on!
- 赛点 来了 - 沃利 加油
Don't get upset though, Wally. Let's go.
沃利 加油别泄气
Yeah!
赢了
It grazed the edge. You fucking saw that.
球擦边了 都他妈看见了吧
It didn't graze the edge.
没擦边
- It changed. You saw that. - It didn't graze the edge.
- 球变向了 这看见了吧 - 没擦边
- No, give me my money. - What the fuck?
- 把钱给我 - 搞什么鬼?
- Give me my money. - This is b--
- 把钱给我 - 这简直...
Give me the money. Give me the money.
把钱给我 钱给我
- Pay me. - Come on.
- 钱给我 - 求你了
Let me hold five for gas money.
留我五块油钱行吗？
No. You shouldn't bet with money you don't have.
不行 你没钱还赌
- How the fuck am I gonna get home? - Walk.
- 车没油了 我怎么回家？ - 用脚
Just let him keep five.
就给他留五块吧
- No. - You've been a dick all night.
- 不行 - 你今晚够混蛋了
- Give me my money. - Just stop being greedy.
- 给钱 - 别再贪这点钱了
- Just give him five to get home! - This is bullshit!
- 留他五块回家钱吧 - 太坑人了
- And you're fucking smiling. - Fuck you!
- 真是厚颜无耻 - 去死吧你
Give me the money. Give me the money.
把钱给我 把钱给我
Fuck you.
去死吧
- Yo, give him his five. - I don't want to.
- 喂 给他留五块吧 - 不给
How the fuck am I gonna get home?
我怎么回家啊
That's what happens when you talk shit.
这就是你吹牛的下场
- It stinks, doesn't it? - Fuck!
- 滋味不好受吧？ - 混蛋
- Where's-- Where's Roger? - Shit.
- 罗杰在哪儿 快出来？ - 该死
- Yeah, I got it. - Yeah, Rog!
- 我来了 - 快来 罗杰
Play this numbnuts for his gas money.
跟这混蛋打一局 把他油钱赢回来
You're gonna play Roger now, okay?
现在你得跟罗杰打 明白吗？
- Let's go, Roger. - Let's go.
- 加油 罗杰 - 加油
- Let's go right now. - You?
- 快点 别磨蹭 - 你？
I won't play you. You're too good.
我不跟你打 你太厉害了
I'll spot you four points.
我让你4分
Fine. Forty dollars.
行 赌40块
【约490美元 3,300人民币 1.5万新台币】
Forty dollars? I don't have forty dollars.
40块？我没这么多钱
You want it? Take it or leave it. I gotta go.
爱打就打 不打拉倒 我得走了
- Forty dollars. - One, two, three...
- 40块 - 一 二 三...
Come on, who's got cash? Who's got cash?
谁还有钱 谁还有钱？
- I got you. - It's Team Wally. Come on.
- 我帮你 - 都帮沃利出点
Pitch in, pitch in. Let's get him home. Come on, come on.
来 来 来 都凑一凑 凑一凑 送他回家
Thank you, everybody. Thank you.
谢谢大家 真谢谢大家
We're gonna get you home. We're gonna get you home.
一定给你赚出回家钱 一定
All right. Great. Great. Nothing? This whole row?
谢谢 谢谢 你们不出钱吗？
Yo, I'll put a side bet.
嘿 我跟你单下一注
How much?
赌多少？
- Five dollars. - You don't got more than that?
- 五块 - 你就这点钱？
Ten. Ooh, you got a little bit of money.
十块 哟 还有点钱嘛
Thank you. Thanks so much.
谢了 非常感谢
♪ You're the only one ♪
♪ 你是我此生唯一的爱 ♪
174 175 176
One seventy-four, 175, 176,
♪ They call, they call me the fat man ♪
♪ 他们老叫我胖子 ♪
177 178 179 180 181...
177, 178, 179, 180, 181...
♪ 'Cause I weight two hundred pounds ♪
♪ 因为我体重两百斤 ♪
181 182 183...
181, 182, 183...
♪ All the girls, they love me ♪
♪ 所有姑娘都爱我 ♪
- The Mouse is back, baby. - ...184, 185...
- 小毛毛回来了 宝贝 - ...184 185...
- Yeah! - ...186
- 太好了 - ...186
♪ 'Cause I know my way around ♪
♪ 因为我懂逗她们开心 ♪
- The Mouse is back, baby! - ...187, 192...
- 小毛毛回来了 宝贝 - ...187 192...
- Oh, this is my part. - ...197, 202, 207...
- 噢 我最爱这段 - ...197 202 207...
♪ Wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
What the fuck are you doing?
你要干什么？
♪ Wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 ♪
Are you out of your mind?
你疯了吗？
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah, wah, wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
Fuck. It's closed.
白跑了 关门了
- Let's just go to the next town. - Next town? That shit is 20 minutes away.
- 去下个镇子吧 - 下个镇子？马上就没油了
You see what we do? Who's a good boy? Who's a good boy?
真是乖孩子 真是乖孩子
- 400... - Come over here, baby.
- 400... - 过来 宝贝
...401 402 403...
...401, 402, 403...
His breathing's a lot better.
他呼吸顺畅多了
We might not have to give the vet any money.
咱们也许不用给兽医送钱了
...407 408
...407, 408.
408. That's 204 each. That's 50-50.
408块 每人204块 咱俩平分
【408美元 约5,000美元 3.4万人民币 15.7万新台币】
Here, here. Okay.
给 拿着
Wally, I was thinking. If you give me the full amount now,
沃利 要不你先把钱都给我
I can give you ten times that when I get back from Japan.
我从日本回来给你十倍
- Stop, stop. Stop, Mouse. - No, no, what do you mean?
- 别闹 小毛毛 - 你什么意思？
You're not gonna fuck me like you do everybody else.
别想拿坑别人的那套来坑我
- You saw the fine. You saw it. - Mouse.
- 你看到罚单了 别忘了 - 毛毛
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that.
我回来还你十倍
- I'll buy you a medallion. - I don't want no fucking medallion, Mouse.
- 我给你买个出租车牌照 - 别拿牌照忽悠我 毛毛
I'll buy you a new cab. Don't give me a hard time about this.
那给你买辆新车 别难为我
There he is!
他在那儿
Hey, motherfucker!
逮到你了 王八蛋
Oh, fuck. Marty. Marty, let's go. Get in the car.
完了 马蒂 马蒂 快上车 快上车
- Okay, just let me do the talking. - Get in the car!
- 别慌 别慌 - 快上车
Look who it is! Let's get this motherfucker!
逮到他了 搞死这王八蛋
Gentlemen.
几位 晚上好
What's going on? How are we doing?
怎么了？哥几个还好吧？
- Give us our money! - What are you talking about?
- 把钱还我们 - 你们在说什么？
- I'm giving this guy some gas. - Look who it is.
- 我正给这哥们加油呢 - 看看这是谁
Don't pull that shit!
别玩这套!
- You fucking hustled us! - I didn't hustle anyone.
- 你他妈设局坑我们 - 我没设局
I know who you are! You're fuckin' Marty Mauser!
我认出你了 你是他妈的马蒂·毛瑟
- Relax! - I don't know who that is!
- 冷静点 - 我就没听说过这个名字
Roger! Stop it! Stop!
罗杰 住手 住手
No, relax. Relax. Relax. Relax.
别 别冲动 有话好说
Out of the fucking car!
滚出这破车
Get out of the fucking car, nigger!
滚出这破车 你这黑鬼
- Why I gotta be-- - Get the fuck out!
- 凭什么要我... - 滚出来
Fuck!
去你们的
- Marty, let's fucking go! - Fuck yourself!
- 马蒂 赶快上车 - 去你们的
Go, go, go, go, go.
走 走 走 走 快走
Wally, watch out! Watch out! The pole!
沃利 注意 注意 电线杆
No! No!
不 不
Wally, the dog. The dog, Wally.
沃利 狗掉了 狗掉下去了 沃利
- Fuck that dog! - I need the dog!
- 管他的狗 - 不能丢下那狗
Fuck the dog,
去他的狗
- Oh, no. No! - and fuck you, man! Fuck you, man!
- 天呐 不 不 - 也去你的 去你的
They'll take this out of my paycheck!
我这回赔大了
My car's fucked up, man! I'm gonna lose my fucking job!
车都废了 得从我工资里扣 我要丢工作了
This is all I got! I got people depending on me!
这是我全部生计 我还有家要养呢
- I got real responsibilities! - I got responsibilities too.
- 我有一大堆担子要扛 - 我也有啊
- No, you don't! - What the fuck you think--
- 你有个屁 - 你他妈觉得...
♪ ...may melt again ♪
♪ ...也许还能融化 ♪
♪ Like winter snow that melts ♪
♪ 像冬雪被四月的雨 ♪
♪ With ♪
♪ 一点点 ♪
♪ April rain ♪
♪ 冲散 ♪
♪ For darling, in my heart ♪
♪ 亲爱的 亲爱的 ♪
♪ You always will remain ♪
♪ 你永远住在我心里 ♪
♪ As summer turns to fall ♪
♪ 即便夏去秋来 ♪
Thank you so much. Thank you.
太感谢你了 太感谢了
I'm gonna make it up to you. All right?
我会补偿你的
Don't be mad at me. Okay?
别生我气 行吗?
I'm gonna get you a new cab. All right?
我会给你买辆新出租 真的
Don't worry about it. Wally, I love you.
别担心 沃利 我的好兄弟
Close my door.
关门好吗
Hey, Marty.
嘿 马蒂
（劳伦斯百老汇球场）
- Hey, Ted. - Hey, Marty. How you doing, man?
- 嘿 泰德 - 嘿 马蒂 近来怎样？
- Is Lawrence here? - Sorry about your loss.
- 劳伦斯在吗？ - 听说令尊的事情了 请节哀
It's all right. Is Lawrence here tonight?
没事的 劳伦斯来了吗？
Uh, yeah. He's around here somewhere.
来了 应该就在里边吧
- Okay. All right. Thank you. - Yeah, yeah.
- 好的 我去找下 谢了 - 行 行
- Good to see you, man. - Yep.
- 欢迎回来伙计 - 嗯
- Hi, Marty. - How you been?
- 马蒂 - 近来可好？
- Nice to see you. - Hello, Marty.
- 好久不见 - 你好 你好
Hey, can I stay in your back room tonight, please?
今晚能借住你后屋吗 求你了
Hey, hey. Got your girl in the back, okay?
嘿 嘿 你的小妞在后头呢 知道吗？
She pregnant. She real upset.
她怀孕了 现在心情挺糟的
Oh, God. Okay. All right.
天呐 好吧 知道了
Uh, let me go talk to her,
我去看看她
but then please don't leave without finding me.
但你千万别走开 我马上回来
- Yeah, I'll be here. Okay. - All right. Nice to see you.
- 放心 我就在这儿 - 好 很高兴见到你
- All right, good to see you. - Okay.
- 也很高兴见到你 - 嗯
Hey. What are you doing here?
嘿 你来这干嘛啊？
I don't mean to bother you. I know you're really busy.
我不想麻烦你 我知道你很忙
- What the hell happened to your face? - I didn't really have anywhere else to go.
- 你这脸怎么回事 谁干的？ - 我真没地方落脚了
- Let me see. - He just started...
- 让我看看 - 他突然就开始...
he just started yelling at me.
他突然就开始朝我大吼
And he was really mad and he was ripping my clothes.
跟疯了一样 还扯我的衣服不撒手
- He did this to you? - He was really scaring me.
- 他打的？ - 他把我吓坏了
I just didn't know where else to go.
我真没别处可去了
Are you mad at me?
你会怪我吗？
Rachel?
瑞秋？
No, it's not Rachel. It's Marty. Open the door.
不 不是瑞秋 是马蒂 开门
Okay. Hang on.
等下
What are you doing here?
你怎么来...
Shame on you.
活该
Hey, Dion. How you doing, man? I really appreciate this.
嘿 迪翁 你好啊 真是打扰了
This is my sister Rachel, by the way.
这是我妹妹 瑞秋
Rachel, this is my buddy, my business partner, Dion.
瑞秋 这是我朋友 也是我生意伙伴迪翁
- Hey. - Hey.
- 嘿 - 嘿
Her place flooded.
她家被水淹了
She needs a place to crash for the night. That's okay, right?
她得借宿一晚 不麻烦吧？
I don't know, man, it's...
我说不好
I know, but I can't have her exposed to mold and spores and shit.
我懂 但我不能让她住在都发霉有毒的地方啊
D, come on, she's eight months pregnant, all right?
迪翁 帮个忙 她都怀孕八个月了 懂吗？
Come on...
帮个忙
That's my nephew.
那孩子是我外甥
I'm not supposed to have people over.
我家规矩不让带别人回来的
She's got a bad situation at home. I can't have her going back there. Please.
她家真没法住了 我不能让她回去 求你了
All right. Come on. You can spend the night.
好吧 好吧 那就住一晚
You just gotta be out of here by tomorrow before my parents get back.
但明天我爸妈回来前就得离开
Okay. No problem.
没问题
We should take advantage of the time we have together.
咱们得趁碰这次碰面好好商量下
You know, really firm up our business plan.
把生意计划好好商量一下
That way, when your dad gets back, he sees how organized we are.
这样你爸一回来 肯定对你另眼相看
Yeah, he's pretty upset.
是啊 他挺失望的
You left us with all of this inventory for eight months.
这堆货丢这儿 你八个月都没管
That's fine. In a few weeks I'll take the championship.
没关系 几周后我拿下世界冠军
We'll be right back on track.
一切都会重回正轨
- Balls are right in here. - Really? Where?
- 球就都在这儿 - 真的？哪儿？
The top box.
最上头的箱子
Thanks.
谢谢
- Whoa. You did the orange? - Yep.
- 哇 你做出橙球了？ - 是
How'd you do the orange?
怎么做的？
I contacted someone at Halex.
我联系了哈克斯公司
They colored the celluloid for me.
他们给塑料上的色
- How? - Money, baby.
- 怎么办到的？ - 花钱 宝贝
Me and my pop, we believe in you.
我和我老爸都看好你
We're invested. That's why he's been so mad.
我们投了钱的 你消失了 所以他挺生气的
Check it out, Rachel.
瞧瞧这个 瑞秋
Here, check out the packaging.
来 看看这包装
（至尊马蒂牌 马蒂·毛瑟冠军赛官方用球）
"Marty Supreme. The official Marty Mauser championship table tennis ball.
“至尊马蒂牌 马蒂·毛瑟冠军赛官方用球”
（精心打造 橙球 让你再也不必穿黑衣）
Professionally made. Orange..."
“精心打造 橙球...”
Orange spheres? You came up with that?
这宣传词 你想出来了？
Yeah. Pretty good, right?
是啊 不错吧
Pretty good? Dion, this is... I'm stunned.
不错吧？迪翁 这让我刮目相看
I'm stunned.
刮目相看
- Hand-drawn too. - You drew this?
- 而且还是手绘的 - 你画的？
- Yeah. - It's inspired.
- 对 - 真是神来之笔
I appreciate it.
多谢夸奖
I don't think you know what you're capable of.
你都不知道自己多有能耐
（至尊马蒂 美国制造）
- Check it out. - Thanks a lot.
- 你瞧瞧 - 过奖
Wow.
哇
it's really nice.
确实很漂亮
- This is your room? - No, it's my brother's.
- 这是你房间？ - 不是 是我弟弟的
You have a brother? You never told me you had a brother.
你还有弟弟？你怎么没跟我说过
It's a younger brother. He moved out.
他已经毕业了 搬出去住了
So his room is free?
那这房间空着？
- Uh, yeah. - Let me get my sister situated.
- 嗯 对 - 我先去安顿一下我妹
- I'll come find you in five minutes. - Okay.
- 五分钟后去找你 - 行
Five minutes.
马上见
I'm really impressed, D.
迪翁 你真让我刮目相看
- Thank you. - Seriously.
- 过奖 - 真佩服你
Special guy.
这家伙真不一般
Let me get the bed comfortable for you, all right?
我去把床弄好 你就安心躺着吧
So are you gonna go out there now?
现在就要走了吗？
Yeah, I gotta figure my plan out for tomorrow.
对 我得琢磨下明天的计划
Why? Plan for what?
什么？什么计划？
Well, I need to get my head together.
我得把心态收拾好
How so?
怎么个收拾法儿？
This rich guy hit me up for a job. I think I'm gonna get in touch with him.
有个有钱佬找我干活 我打算联系他
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 是啊
- A job for what? What job? - It doesn't matter. Just to get to Japan.
- 什么活？干什么？ - 不重要 能去日本就行
- For the championship? - Yeah.
- 去打世锦赛吗？ - 对
Wow.
哇
Everything in my life is falling apart, but I'm gonna figure it out.
生活一团糟 我会找到出路的
Do you need any help? I could help you.
要帮忙吗？我可以帮你
- No, it's all right. It's all right. - Can I do anything?
- 没事 不用了 - 要帮忙吗？
Are you hungry?
你饿吗？
- No. - You sure?
- 不饿 - 确定？
Uh, I'll just be in the other room, all right?
你休息吧 我就在隔壁
- Dion, I've never seen anything like this. - I told you, man.
- 迪翁 这球是绝无仅有的 - 我就说吧 老兄
Man, we have to have a big catch-up
老兄 咱们得好好叙叙旧
'cause this is the greatest thing that's happened to me in the last eight months.
这是八个月来我经历的最好的事
Who would've thought? Halex?
找哈克斯 真天才啊
Good morning. Rockwell Ink.
早上好 罗克韦尔墨业公司
Yes, hi, can I speak to Milton Rockwell, please?
喂 你好 麻烦帮我接米尔顿·罗克韦尔先生
He's not in at the moment. Can I take a message?
他暂时不在 需要留个言吗？
Okay, when are you expecting him?
好吧 他什么时候回来？
Well, he's working off-site today.
他今天外出
- Again, can I take a message? - It's hot.
- 要不要留言？ - 小心烫
Thank you so much.
太感谢了
Can you make some for my sister for when she wakes up?
等我妹醒了 能给她也弄份吗？
- She'll be really hungry. - Hello?
- 她肯定饿得要命 - 喂？
You said off-site where?
你刚说他外出 具体在哪儿？
I'm sorry, I can't give you that information.
抱歉 这个信息我不能透露
- Would you like to leave a message or not? - Yes.
- 您到底要不要留言？ - 要
Can you apologize to him on my behalf?
能替我向他道个歉吗？
I was the young gentleman that was supposed to have breakfast
我是原本今早要和他一起吃早饭的
with him this morning.
那个年轻人
- I'm not familiar. - From his son's battalion.
- 我对这事不熟 - 就是他儿子那个营的
I'm sorry, I-- I don't know anything about that.
抱歉 我 我对此一无所知
I have some personal belongings of his son's I was supposed to give to him.
我手上有他儿子的遗物 要交给他
Letters and mementos and such, but I messed up and I overslept.
信件啊纪念品什么的 但我睡过头来不及了
I'm leaving town today, but I could mail it to him if that's easier.
我今天就要走了 要不我回头寄给他？
- No, no, no. - No? Okay.
- 不 不 不 不行 - 不行？好的
How about this, why don't you try giving a call over to the Morosco Theatre.
这样吧 你给莫罗斯科剧院打个电话问问
The Morosco Theatre.
好 莫罗斯科剧院
So, I'm like what? What am I doing?
所以我算什么？我这是干嘛啊
Coming up here to wreck my night.
真不该来 好好晚上被你毁了
Honest, Mama, I didn't even know you were coming here.
说真的 妈 你怎么会在这种地方
I'm through with you playing games.
我受够了你这套把戏
I was just coming for a good time.
我只是来找点乐子
I heard this was where all the call girls gather.
听说应召女郎都在这儿
I'm trying to rebuild my life here. Don't you understand that?
我在努力攒钱重建生活 你不明白吗？
More like selling out to the highest bidder.
你这是出卖自己吧
You've got no right to judge me, Jed.
你没资格评判我 小杰
I fought tooth and nail for every shred of happiness
我拼尽全力才换来那么一点幸福
- I've ever found while you... - Right, and what did you give to me?
- 我拼尽全力... - 那你给过我什么？
You never believed in me. Not once!
你从没相信过我 一次都没有
You wanna wallow in self-pity? Well, here's an oven, Jed!
少装可怜 你自生自灭吧
Alma!
阿尔玛 别
I'm all right, Henry.
我没事 亨利
- Just give us a minute, please. - My mama is a dirty bird.
- 给我们点时间 - 我妈就是个婊子
Be careful now, Jedidiah.
嘴放干净点 杰迪代亚
And that fancy dress you put her in is the only thing keeping in the stench!
你给她的那身花衣服 只是掩盖她的耻辱
Don't you lay a hand on my child.
别打我儿子
I-I'm sorry, uh...
我...抱歉
Mama, what did I do?
妈 完蛋了
Go! Run!
走 快跑
- The door is locked. - Oh, my God.
- 谁把门锁了 - 真会打断
You've gotta be kidding me!
谁锁的啊
For Christ's sake, did somebody put a latch on the door?
正演戏呢？谁干的 谁给锁的啊
- Oh, God. - I thought we had a good rhythm going.
- 噢天呐 - 我们刚进入节奏
A good rhythm going? On what planet is that a good rhythm
进入节奏？演成这样叫节奏？还我们？
- if you're alone in a room? - I was in it.
- 你不顾其他人吗？ - 我入戏了
It's like I wasn't even there. In it? In what?
搞得跟我不在场一样 入戏？独角戏？
- Glenn, I couldn't get a word out. - I understand. We're gonna fix it.
- 格伦 我连句台词都插不进去 - 我懂 咱们会解决的
- That's what a rehearsal process is for. - Fuck's sake.
- 排练就是为了解决这些 - 真绝了
Let's lose this, by the way. Everybody take five.
先停一下吧 大家休息五分钟
Do me a favor, everybody...
帮个忙 各位...
Somebody needs to tell him something.
得有人跟他说说这事
- It's impossible. - Impossible.
- 真离谱 - 真离谱
- Do you want some water? - Yes.
- 喝水吗？ - 喝
- Let me bring you some. - God.
- 我去给你拿点 - 天呐
Hey, Kay.
嘿 凯
Hey, it's Marty.
是我 马蒂
From London.
伦敦那个
What are you doing here?
你怎么跑这了？
Well, I got a friend in the stagehands union.
来见个朋友 他搞舞台的
I was dropping something off for him.
我过来给他送点东西
- You watched that? - Yeah, I hope that's okay.
- 你刚才看了吧 - 看了 没关系吧
Oh, God.
噢 天呐
Hey, I can't believe you're acting again.
没想到你又开始演戏了
That wasn't acting. He won't let me act.
那不叫演戏 他老抢我戏
Yeah, no, that looked frustrating. What's the deal with that guy?
挺气人的 那家伙什么来头？
Don't get me started.
别提了
Yeah, you were running circles around him.
即便被抢戏 你也比他演得好
Of course I am.
那还用说
Yeah. It was unbelievable.
对 演得真好
He stays up for three days in a row
他连续三天不睡觉
because his character is supposed to be tired.
就是为了要演得累
- It's obnoxious. - Oh, God.
- 真是疯了 - 对啊
If he's so committed, why'd he stop the scene?
他要真投入 怎么会因为那锁打断？
Why didn't he punch his hand through the screen,
干嘛不一脚踹开？
unlock it from the other side?
接着演呢？
- Right? That's what I would've done. - Glenn!
- 对吧？换我会这么干 - 格伦
- Yeah. - Glenn!
- 这就来 - 格伦
- Yes. Thank you. Yes. - I need to talk to you.
- 好的 来了 - 我跟你说句话
- Yes, what? - What? What? What?
- 怎么了？ - 你说怎么了
This kid understands the character better than he does.
这小子比他更懂这个角色
Excuse me?
你说什么？
- Tell him what you just told me. - No, I don't want to.
- 把你刚说的话告诉他 - 不 我不想说
No, tell him.
说吧 告诉他
I was just saying you didn't really seem like you were in the scene is all.
我说你不像是真入戏了
- Uh, who is this? - He's nobody.
- 他懂不懂戏？ - 当局者迷
- That's the point. - Also, you know, in my experience,
- 旁观者清 - 而且 在我看来
only children hold a knife like this.
只有玩过家家才这样拿刀
If it's a serious fight, you hold your knife like this,
要是真打 刀该这样拿
- with the blade square to your wrist. - This is not a street fight.
- 刀要在上面 - 这又不是街头斗殴
Okay, well, if you're not going for realistic,
好吧 既然你们不求真的话
you might as well add a little flair.
还得再加点花样
Like that.
就像这样
- Cut it out. - Right, Kay?
- 别闹了 - 对吧 凯？
Yeah, okay. Thanks for the tutorial. Thank you very much.
行了 行了 谢了你的教程 谢谢
Thank you very much indeed. That's all we need today. Thank you.
真是太感谢了 抓紧走吧 谢谢
- Best of luck, Kay. Best of luck. - Get him out!
- 加油 凯 - 送他出去
We no longer require your presence. Thank you very much.
这里不需要你了 谢谢 抓紧走吧
Well, with all due respect...
恕我直言...
And yet every set cost more than $5,000.
每套布景竟然都要5000多块
I can't just snap my fingers and get your money and your wife into alignment.
要让您太太高兴又少花钱 真办不到啊
I pay you to say no.
那我花钱雇你干嘛
She seems to think that this is carte blanche.
让她感觉有主导权 又要控制她开销
I can't just perform the impossible here.
这根本做不到啊
If you can't control her, I will find someone else who can.
要是你做不到 我就另请他人
Asshole.
混蛋
Mr. Rockwell. Mr. Rockwell.
罗克韦尔先生 请等一下
- What? - Hey. Marty Mauser. Nice to see you.
- 干什么？ - 是我 马蒂·毛瑟 又见面了
Did you call my office and say you're friends with my son?
是不是你冒充我儿子战友给我办公室打的电话？
- Yes. But... - Goddamn it!
- 是的 但是... - 混蛋
I had no other way to get in touch with you. Please.
我没别的办法联络您了 请您听我说
I wanna revisit our conversation about Japan.
我想再谈谈去日本的事
I reconsidered it and I wanna do it. I think it's a great idea.
我重新考虑过了 我想去 我觉得主意不错
The event's next week. I've made alternate plans.
比赛就在下周 我已经有别的计划了
What other plans? Okay, it was your idea.
别的计划？这最初可是您的主意
It's a fantastic idea. Let's just have a conversation about this for two seconds.
这主意棒极了 求您给我两分钟谈谈
What are you doing? Hey. Hey. Mr. Rockwell.
你干什么呢？嘿 嘿 罗克韦尔先生
Please, let's both be pragmatists about this.
求您了 咱们务实些
Put your personal feelings about me aside for a second.
把私人感情放一边
You and I both know how much value I would add with Endo.
您也知道 我和远藤合作能带来多少好处
In an exhibition on his home turf?
在他的主场打表演赛？
Imagine it. I'd be like a stick of dynamite.
势必会引爆全场
Whatever you have planned, the alternative,
不管您的备选计划是什么
it's gonna pale in comparison.
都比不上这个
Please give me two minutes.
请给我两分钟
We have enough common ground to figure this out. Please!
我们还能达成共识 求您了
- All right, get in the car. - Really? Thank you.
- 行吧 上车说 - 真的？谢谢
Tommy, let's go.
汤米 开车
Hey. Hey! Hey! Hey!
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
You son of a bitch. I gave you the idea!
你这王八蛋 桌球还是我给你引荐的
I'm sorry. Ms. Stone wanted to let you know
不好意思 凯·斯通女士让我转告你
that she'd love to have lunch with you.
她想与您共进午餐
- Ms. Stone? - Yes.
- 凯·斯通？ - 是的
My God, I'm so late.
天呐 我迟到太久了
Come on. What do you care?
在意这些干嘛
You're the star. Gotta feel pretty good, right?
你可是主角 心里应该爽才对
I mean, why'd you even stop in the first place?
话说 你当初为啥退出演艺圈？
I wanted security, and I got pregnant,
我想要个保障 结果怀孕了
and he pressured me, and I settled.
他又给我压力 我就答应了
Well, I mean, clearly, you're doing the right thing now
眼下你是走对路了
and it sounds like he's paying you back with interest.
而且他看起来正加倍补偿你
- Who is? - Your husband.
- 谁补偿？ - 你丈夫
I mean, he's funding your whole show, right?
你的演出都是他出钱吧？
Where'd you get that idea?
哪来的这种想法？
I overheard him complaining about it in the lobby.
我在走廊无意听到他嘟囔这些
- Complaining? - Yeah, about the costs.
- 嘟囔？ - 是的 抱怨开销太大
He can go fuck himself.
让他滚一边去吧
Completely. You know what you should do,
没错 彻底滚蛋
you should leech him for every penny he's worth,
你应该把他榨干
assume your place as the biggest star on the planet,
把自己捧成最红的星
and then you rub it in his smug little face.
然后狠狠打他那张自大嘴脸
Thank you, but I'm really not looking for life advice from you.
谢谢 我可不想听你的人生建议
No, I'm just saying you clearly never needed him in the first place.
不 我只是说 你根本不用靠他
Like with me, I'm never accepting anyone's help.
就像我 绝不靠谁帮忙
I gotta do it completely on my own. Purely on the basis of my own talent.
我只靠我自己 靠我的手艺
Otherwise it's, like, the success won't even count.
不然的话 奖杯都被玷污了
But that's just me.
这只是我自己的观念
Yes, well, that's very easy to say.
说起来倒是容易
Well, it's easy to say but it's sure not easy to do.
说起来容易 做起来可真难
I mean, you know that. That's why you cashed out.
你懂的 所以你才拿钱退圈了
Let me ask you something.
我问你个事
Do you make money at this little table tennis thing?
你靠这门小桌球挣到钱了吗？
- Not yet. - Do you have a job?
- 还没呢 - 你有工作吗？
No. I mean, table tennis is my job.
没有 我是说 桌球就是我的工作
How do you live?
那你靠什么糊口？
I live with the confidence
我靠信念
that if I believe in myself, the money will follow.
只要我相信自己 钱自然会来的
Ultimately, my struggle isn't even about money.
归根结底 我奋斗的重点不是钱
- How do you pay rent? - I don't.
- 你怎么交房租？ - 不交
- You're avoiding the question. - No, I'm not avoiding anything.
- 你是在回避问题 - 不 我没回避
How do you plan on eating food today?
那今天你打算怎么吃饭？
Honestly, I was gonna order room service the second you leave.
说实话 我打算你一走就叫客房送饭来
- Nice. - Yeah. Nice.
- 真行啊 - 是啊 是啊
And what do you plan to do if this whole dream of yours doesn't work out?
要是你这梦想行不通 你有什么打算？
That doesn't even enter my consciousness.
我压根不会想这种事情
Okay. Well, maybe it should.
好吧 也许你得考虑一下现实了
Wow.
哇
You sound like my mom. No offense.
你这口气真像我妈 随便说说
And you sound like a child.
你倒像个小屁孩
Oh, yeah? Clearly I'm old enough.
是吗？我可够成熟的
And what is that supposed to mean?
你什么意思？
That I'm old enough to fuck you in your hotel room
成熟到能在你东山再起的时候
in the middle of your big comeback.
在酒店干你一场 还是你的酒店
You're disgusting.
你真下流
Break a leg.
祝演出顺利
No, I know, but I was out of town
我明白 不过我在外地
so I only just received it yesterday for the first time.
这信我昨天才刚收着
Well, look, not coming to Japan is not an option.
去日本行程已经订好了 改不了了
Okay, well, just let Mr. Sethi know that a cashier's check in the full amount
麻烦跟拉姆·塞西说 全额的
is already on the way to him. It's in the mail.
银行担保的赔付支票已经寄出
No, that's fine, but just...
不介意 只是...
I don't want any confusion about my attendance.
别在现场一见到我就惊讶
I'm gonna be there. I'm gonna be there when the tournament starts.
我一定到场 开赛时肯定见得着我
- I got it! - Yes! Yes! Yes!
- 找到了 - 太好了 太好了 太好了
How much do you think?
能值多少钱？
- This is not real. - What do you mean it's not real?
- 这是假货 - 假货？你什么意思？
- Total fake. - It came from the neck of a millionaire.
- 完全赝品 - 这可是从大富婆脖子上摘下来的
I saw it come off her neck.
我亲眼看着摘下来的
I don't care where it came from. It's total garbage.
我不管来路 这玩意不值钱
- Costume jewelry. - Costume jewelry?
- 装饰用的仿制品 - 装饰用的？
- Yeah. - Oh, fuck.
- 嗯 - 该死
If you want, I can give you two bucks for it.
想卖的话 我最多给你两块钱
- Hello. - Hey, Dion. It's me.
- 喂 - 喂 迪翁 是我
How are you doing?
忙不忙啊
Hey, where have you been? You promised me we'd have a list of distributors.
你跑哪去了？你答应过要准备经销商名单的
My dad lands tonight.
我爸今晚就回来了
I'll come back now and give you my undivided attention.
我这就回去 全力做这件事
Let me just talk to my sister for a second.
先让我跟我妹说句话
Rachel, Marty's on the phone.
瑞秋 马蒂来电话了
- Hi. Where are you? - Hi, Rachel, listen.
- 喂 你在哪儿？ - 喂 瑞秋 听好了
There's a dog collar in my jacket, okay?
我夹克里有个狗项圈
I know a guy who lost a dog out in New Jersey.
有个人狗在新泽西丢了
He'll pay a big reward.
他会付大笔赏金
Also, there's a set of car keys in a bowl by the front door.
还有 他家车钥匙在门口小碗里
- You see them? - Yeah.
- 看见了吗？ - 看见了
Grab the keys, and make sure Dion doesn't see you do it.
拿上钥匙 把车开来 别让迪翁瞧见
Hey, Dion.
嘿 迪翁
Can you go to the store and grab me some ginger?
能去商店帮我买点生姜吗？
I'm having really bad morning sickness.
我晨吐反应特别厉害
Hi.
嗨
Sorry, station's closed.
抱歉 加油站打样了
That's okay. We're not looking for service.
没事 我们不是来加油的
Did you see a dog come around here?
你们附近有看到跑丢的狗吗？
Nah, I ain't seen nothing. You seen a dog?
没 没见着 你瞧见狗了吗？
- He's this tall. - When did you lose it?
- 差不多这么高 - 什么时候丢的？
A few days ago.
几天前
There's a pound down in Cranberry. About five miles that way.
克兰伯里有个收容所 往那走大概八公里
- Maybe try there. - I called there.
- 问问他们 - 我打过电话了
- Sorry, can't help you. - Okay.
- 抱歉 帮不上忙 - 好吧
Thank you.
谢谢
They didn't see anything.
没人看到狗
Let's go try that place.
咱们去那里试试
Hello.
有人在家吗？
Hello?
有人吗?
- Where are you going? - Just gonna check out back.
- 你去哪？ - 我去后面瞧瞧
Oh, shit. Moses.
我去 摩西
"We're grateful to the record manufacturers and artists
“我们非常感谢全国各地的唱片商和艺术家们”
all over the country."
“全国各地的艺术家们”
Hey, buddy. Hey. Hey, Moses.
嘿 狗狗 嘿 嘿 摩西
It's Marty. Hey, buddy.
是我 马蒂 乖狗狗
Oh, fuck.
该死
Hey, buddy.
乖狗狗
Moses. Moses!
摩西 摩西
Hey, buddy. Calm down. Let's get you home.
冷静 冷静 我来带你回家
You wanna go home, right? Let's go home.
想不想回家？走 咱们回家
Okay. Hey. No, no, no, no, no.
好了 别 别 别
"And that was Peppermint Harris
“刚才为您播放的是佩珀敏特·哈里斯”
"and that great record of his...
“以及他的那首金曲...”
"But it's time to hang up the old blunderbuss for now.
“不过现在是时候暂别这档节目了”
"Remember, if you want any..."
“记住 如果你想...”
- Hi, how are you? - Can I help you?
- 你好？ - 有事吗？
We were just searching the area for a lost dog.
我们狗丢了 正在找狗
- "We"? - My husband and I.
- 你们？ - 我和我丈夫
We lost our dog a couple of days ago out near the gas station
我们的狗几天前在加油站附近丢了
and they told us to come and check over here...
他们叫我们来这边瞧瞧...
- seeing that you're the closest house. - Who?
- 因为你是最近的一户人家 - 谁？
Who? Which gas station?
谁让你来的？哪个加油站？
- I don't know. - Hey!
- 我说不上来 - 嘿
It was one of the guys that work there.
是加油站伙计说的
- Oh, man, I'm so excited you're back. - There he is!
- 老兄 你终于来了 - 我丈夫
- I think you might've found our dog. - You're trespassing.
- 看来你捡到了我们的狗 - 你们在私闯民宅
No. I'm sorry, that's not our intention. We heard barking in the back.
别误会 抱歉打扰了 我们听到后院有狗叫
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我不懂你在说啥
My dog. You found it.
我的狗 被你捡到了
I didn't find any dog.
我没捡过狗
Are you sure?
你确定？
Yeah, I'm sure. Are you sure?
我当然确定 你呢？
Yeah...
是啊...
I looked through your window.
我趴着你那窗户
- I saw my dog. - You were looking through my window?
- 看到了我的狗 - 你竟然偷看我窗户？
Yeah, It was a good thing I did, right?
是啊 不看怎么找到的
Get the hell off my property before I call the police.
趁我报警前 赶紧滚出我的地盘
You call? I should call the police.
该叫警察的是我才对
Okay. You wanna get a closer look at him?
行啊 要不要再核实下看清楚？
- You wanna closer look? - Yes, please.
- 近距离看清楚？ - 是的 麻烦了
Okay, good, good. I'll give you a closer look.
行 我就让你看清楚
Hey!
嘿
Calm down.
冷静点
I am calm.
我很冷静
- If I see your kike face... - Are you serious?
- 你这张犹太脸... - 你认真的？
- ...looking through my window again... - Marty, get in the car!
- ...再敢偷瞄我窗户 - 马蒂 快上车
- Are you out of your mind? - ...I'm gonna shoot it off.
- 你疯了吗？ - ...我我就把你脸打烂
There's no need for that. We're leaving. Marty, get in!
别把事搞大 我们这就走 马蒂 快上车
What are you doing?
你疯了吗？
- Get in the car, Marty! - No! I need the dog!
- 马蒂 快上车 - 不行 必须得拿到狗
- Get in the car! - Next one's going to your face.
- 快上车 - 看我不打爆你的脸
Marty, get...
马蒂 快...
No, no, no, no! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
哦 不 不 不 别开枪 别开枪
Rachel! Help me!
瑞秋 快帮我
Marty, get in the car!
马蒂 快上车
Come on, come on, come on. Hurry! Hurry!
快点 快点 快跑 快跑
Get in! Get in! Get in!
上车 上车 上车
Go, go, go straight, Rachel. Go, go!
开车 开车 开车 快开 瑞秋 快
Straight! Go! Go in the corn!
超前开 快 开进玉米地
- Go, go, go, go, go, go, go. - Oh, my god! Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
- 快开 快开 快开 - 天呐 天呐 天呐
Oh, no!
天呐
（摩西）
- Hello? - Hi.
- 喂 - 喂
Hi, did you...
你是不是...
Did you by any chance lose a dog named Moses?
你是不是丢了一只叫摩西的狗？
Yeah, I did. Why?
丢了 怎么了？
Oh, you did? Amazing! 'Cause we just found him.
真的？太好了 我们刚好捡到他
- For real? - I did, yeah.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
- How is he? How's his breathing? - You know what?
- 他怎么样 还喘不喘？ - 实话跟你说
When we got him, his breathing was a little shallow.
刚开始他呼吸挺虚的
- The money. - Give me your address.
- 赶紧谈钱 - 把你地址给我
I'm gonna come right now.
我马上到
Well, that's the thing.
事情没那么简单
The thing? What do you mean?
你什么意思？
'Cause you know in situations like these it's...
这事儿按惯例
it's kind of customary to give the person a reward, no?
应该给点赏钱吧？
Yeah, fine. How much you have in mind?
好吧 那你想要多少？
- It's too much money. It's too much. - No, say it. He's fucking loaded.
- 开价太高了吧？ - 不高 他有的是钱
- Hello? - Tell him.
- 喂 - 快说
I was thinking maybe $2,000 seems fair for this kind of a thing.
要我说2000挺合适的
That seems pretty fair to me.
挺公道的
- Two thousand. - You're joking, right?
- 只要2000 - 你开玩笑吧？
- No, no. No. - That's fucking ridiculous.
- 没开玩笑 - 你他妈在耍我吧
Look, look...
听着 听着...
I know it's really not your problem, but...
我知道这跟你没关系 但...
I'm about to have a baby, and, look, I got no husband right now.
但我快生了 而且我一个人 没丈夫
I got no job, and this money would really, really help me.
也没工作 这钱就算行善积德了
And, you know, let's be good people and...
咱们行善吧
You realize I got that dog for free at the pound, right?
那狗是我在收容所白领的 知道吗？
Well, that's kind of the wrong way to look at it.
这么想就错了
- Oh, really? - Yeah, really.
- 错了？ - 对 错了
How am I supposed to look at it?
那我该怎么想？
'Cause let's just say that I'm not calling about a dog.
比方说我不是在谈狗
Let's say that I'm calling about your mother,
比方说我是在说你母亲
and I'm a doctor, and I gotta perform emergency surgery on her
我是医生 要做急救手术
or she's gonna die. What are you gonna do?
不然她会死 你该怎么办？
Refuse the surgery because you got your mother for free?
你能因她不是买来的就不救吗？
No! That's crazy. You're gonna take the surgery
不会的 你会救你母亲
- because you love your mother. - That's the stupidest thing I ever heard.
- 因为你爱她 - 这是什么胡扯比喻
Well, then I guess you don't know anything about love.
那就说明你不懂爱
All right, forget it. Give me your address, okay? I'll come now.
行了 别扯了 把地址给我 我现在就来
- I'll bring you the cash. - I'm sorry, but no.
- 带钱来 - 抱歉 但不行
- No? - No.
- 不行？ - 不行
it's really not your fault, and you sound like a very nice person.
别误会 你听着也像好人
It's just I've been ripped off one too many times in the past,
但我以前被坑过太多次了
and I'm just not willing to let that happen to me again.
这回不能冒险
So, we're just gonna need to find a way to get me the money first.
所以 这次必须先拿到钱
- You know? Yeah. - Yeah?
- 你懂吗？ - 懂
Listen to me, you fucking dumb bitch.
给我听好了 你这蠢娘们
- You're not getting one red cent... - What is wrong with you?
- 你一分钱都别想拿到 - 你嘴怎么那么脏？
...without me laying eyes on him.
....除非我亲眼见到狗
- If you really don't give a shit about... - You understand, sister?
- 你真不在乎的话... - 听明白了吗 妹子？
...your dog that you got for free, how about I donate him to medical science?
...既然狗是白领的 我就把他送去做实验
- Would that be something you want? - I told you this wasn't gonna work.
- 你想那样吗？ - 我就说这行不通
（旧车行）
I should have known better. What am I doing?
我早该料到 我到底在想啥
- It was a terrible idea. - Marty!
- 真是个烂主意 - 马蒂
- It was moronic. - I'm sorry, I was--
- 烂透了 - 抱歉 我...
I'm sorry. I was trying to give it a shot.
抱歉 我只是想碰碰运气
- It's not your fault. It was stupid. - All right. Calm down.
- 不怪你 是这事就不对头 - 好了 别慌
What color is the dog?
那狗是什么颜色的？
Why? Who cares? It's brown.
问这干嘛？棕色的
Okay, because my boss knows all of the local breeders,
是这样 我老板认识所有狗贩
and maybe we can get one that looks the same,
没准能找只长差不多的
and the owner won't be able to tell the difference.
他不一定看得出来
You don't think he's gonna recognize his own dog that he loves?
他能认不出他心爱的狗？
- But I'm saying maybe not at first. - I should be working on my game right now.
- 我是说不会立马发现 - 我现在该练球的
Instead, I'm in a used car lot
结果跑到这个旧车场
making a mockery of my life, doing prank calls.
丢人现眼 整这些没用的电话
- What are you guys doing? - Hey, pal. What are you still doing up?
- 你们从哪来的？ - 老兄 你怎么还没睡？
Keep your voice down. My parents are sleeping.
小点声 我爸妈在睡觉
- I didn't know they were back. - I told you they were back.
- 他们回来了？ - 我告诉过你了
- Where's my dad's car? - It's in the garage.
- 我爸的车呢？ - 就在车库
You're not gonna believe, Dion, when I tell you the day that we had.
我们今天经历的 绝对让你惊掉下巴
- You tricked me. - No, I didn't. What are you talking about?
- 你骗了我 - 没有啊 你瞎说什么
- Yes, you did, you lying bitch. - Whoa.
- 你确实骗了 你这骗人的死丫头 - 喔
Hey, you watch your mouth, you fat piece of shit.
嘴放干净点 你这死肥猪
- Don't talk to me like that. - Don't talk to him like that.
- 不许你骂我 - 别骂他
He's one of my favorite people on the planet.
他可是我最铁的朋友
- Tell him not to talk to me like that. - Don't talk to her like that.
- 叫他别骂我 - 你也别骂她
- Don't talk to him like that. - Keep it down.
- 别骂他 - 小声点
I'm the one that told her to do it. She wouldn't have if I didn't.
别怪她 是我让她干的
- Give me the car keys. - Okay, they're right here. Okay?
- 把车钥匙给我 - 行 就在这儿 给你
- We got into a little fender bender... - What?
- 有点小剐蹭... - 什么？
...but it's gonna be okay.
...但没大碍
- It's minor damage. I can pay for it. - How? When?
- 就是小伤 我会赔的 - 拿什么赔？什么时候赔？
Dion, it's very late right now. We should all get a little bit of rest.
迪翁 这么晚了 咱们都该歇歇了
I'll smooth it over with your father at breakfast.
明天早饭时我来跟你爸解释
- I know your father-- - You're not staying here!
- 有我在你别... - 你们不能在这过夜
- We got no other place to stay. - You guys gotta go.
- 我们没别的地方可去了 - 你们必须得走
No. Dion. We have to stay.
不 迪翁 我们必须得留下
- We have nowhere-- Dion. Stop it. - No. Shh.
- 没别的地方... 迪翁 别这样 - 不行 嘘
She's eight months pregnant. Are you out of your mind?
她都怀孕八个月了 你疯了吗？
- Please can we just talk about it? - Keep your voice down.
- 我们坐下来谈谈好不好 - 声音小点
Gonna throw us out in the street in the dead of night?
深更半夜把我们赶出去是吧
- Yeah, yeah. Get in. - We've got nowhere to go.
- 没错 进去收拾东西 - 我们真没地方去了
Get your shit and leave.
收拾东西赶紧走
Do you have any idea what we've been through today?
知道我们今天经历了什么吗？
I'm not talking to you.
我不理你
You're not talking to me?
你不理我？
Now you're not talking to me, period?
你彻底不打算理我了？
Unbelievable.
这啥事啊
Must be nice being born with a silver spoon in your mouth.
含金汤匙的人
Meanwhile, some of us have to work for a living.
体会不到谋生的苦
You ever heard that word, "work"?
你懂什么叫谋生吗？
Instead of doodling in your room all day?
整天在房里瞎玩
Throwing your friends out on the street...
竟然把朋友往街上赶...
Can you not stare at us? Can you look at the wall?
别盯着我们看 看墙去
You're creeping me out.
别像监狱看守那样
Where are we gonna go? Because...
我们能去哪儿？
- I'm sorry. You have a bed right here... - It's okay.
- 对不住 这儿明明有床... - 没事的
- ...and I could be sleeping on it. - It's okay.
- ...我本来能睡这的 - 没事的
And I got a baby in me. I got a baby in me.
而且我怀着孩子 我怀着孩子
It's okay. See what you're doing?
没事的 看你干的好事
You're throwing a pregnant woman out on the street in the dead of the night.
大半夜的把孕妇赶到街上
It's gonna live on your conscience forever.
这事会让你一辈子良心不安
- Why would you do this to yourself? - I'm sorry.
- 干嘛要自找苦吃？ - 对不起
Can I have a moment with her, please? Just to comfort her,
给我几分钟行吗？我得安抚下她
in privacy with my sister, please?
让我跟我妹单独呆会儿
- Keep her voice down. - I'm gonna try, but I gotta calm her down.
- 让她小声点 - 我尽量 我尽量 我先把她安抚好
Sorry.
抱歉
I don't know what to do. I don't know what to do.
这怎么办啊 这怎么办啊
That was really good.
演得真好
- That was amazing, Rachel. - Thank you.
- 瑞秋 演得太好了 - 谢谢
That was so good, it might work.
太好了 这招也许行得通
- Where are we gonna go if he kicks us out? - He might actually let us stay now.
- 要是被赶了 下一步去哪？ - 他估计不会赶咱们了
That acting was so brilliant.
多亏你这套苦肉计
- Are you actually crying? - No. Marty, what are you doing?
- 你还真哭出来了？ - 不要 马蒂 你干嘛
- What is that? - What?
- 这是什么？ - 怎么了？
Is this makeup?
这是化妆吗？
Hold on.
别急
Just wait. Because I can explain. It's not my fault. Okay?
别急 听我解释 这不怪我 好吗？
No talking.
别说话
- I didn't have a choice, you know? - Stop. Stop, please. Stop.
- 我也是被逼无奈 你懂吗？ - 够了 求你别说了 住嘴
- Rachel, stop. - I needed to get out.
- 瑞秋 别说了 - 我必须得逃出来
- See how calm I am? It's not gonna last. - Yeah.
- 我冷静吗？但快到头了 - 嗯
Get the fuck out of here.
给我滚出去
- No. What I think-- - Get the fuck out of here.
- 不 要走... - 赶快滚出去
- I think that we should both go because... - Stop.
- 要走一起走 因为... - 闭嘴
This is the kinda shit my mother would do to me.
跟我妈一个套路
How could you of all people do this to me, the way I treat you?
我对你这么好 你怎么下得了手
- How could I do this to you? - Yes, knowing what I'm going through?
- 我下得了手？ - 对 你怎么下得了手？
- How about what you're doing to me? - Stop. Shh. What are you doing...
- 那你怎么忍心对我下手 - 别吵 嘘 你在干嘛
Have you ever for one second thought about what you're doing--
你有认真想过自己在做啥吗？
- Stop. - Shush yourself, you narcissistic prick.
- 闭嘴 - 你才闭嘴 你这自私自大的王八蛋
- Stop. What are you doing? - Don't touch me!
- 别闹了 你在干什么？ - 别碰我
- You're gonna wake my parents up. Shut up. - Enough about your fucking parents.
- 要把我爸妈吵醒了 闭嘴 - 去他妈的爸妈
Aren't you, like, 30 years old?
30了还爸妈？
You realize I'm due in four weeks?
知道吗？我还有四周就要生了
- I am due in four weeks! - It's not my baby.
- 四周就要生了 - 孩子又不是我的
And it's his baby, by the way. It's his fucking baby.
就是他的孩子 这王八蛋的孩子
He's lying about that too.
他连这种事都骗了你
- What's going on in my house? - I was just having some friends over, Dad.
- 在我家闹什么呢？ - 爸 我只是请了几个朋友来
Buddy, how are you?
晚上好
Hey, we have a meeting with Spalding first thing in the morning
嘿 明早咱们得和斯伯丁开个会
【斯伯丁:知名美国运动器材公司】
- for the Supreme samples. - Dion, come on. Give me a break.
- 谈至尊球的事 - 迪翁 醒醒吧
That's never gonna happen.
别做白日梦了
- You've taken my son's money. - What are you talking about?
- 你已经骗了我儿子的钱了 - 您在说什么呢？
I don't believe it. D, don't you see what's happening?
迪翁 你看不出来吗？
- Unbelievable. Un-fucking... - You're conning my son all along.
- 我受不了了... - 你一直在骗我儿子
- I am not conning your son. - You're taking all his money.
- 我没骗你儿子 - 你卷走了他所有的钱
No, I give him meaning. All you do is give him money.
不对 我让他有追求 你用钱来敷衍
- I give him purpose. - You listen to me!
- 我给了他奋斗目标 - 你给我听好
- Get out of here right now! - He won't even fucking look at you, he's so petrified of you.
- 给我滚蛋 - 你天天骂他 看看他被你吓得
What are we gonna do, huh? Where do you expect us to go?
我们怎么办？我们能去哪？
You really want me to sleep on the street? I'm pregnant.
你真想让我睡大街？我怀孕了
No, no, no. Dion! Dion!
别 别 别 迪翁 迪翁
All right, I gotta tell you something, Rachel. It's not intended to be mean.
行吧 瑞秋 我开门见山说吧 没别的意思
I have a purpose. You don't.
我有人生目标 而你没有
If you think that's some sort of blessing, it's not.
别以为这是好事
It puts me at a huge life disadvantage.
你反倒在拖累我
It means I have an obligation to see a very specific thing through.
我有个非常明确的目标
And with that obligation comes sacrifice, okay?
我得为它放弃一切 明白吗？
My life is the product of all the choices I've had to make.
我是一步步才走到今天的
Your life is the product of...
而你那人生...
I don't even know what your life is the product of.
我实在不知道咋形容
You're making it up as you go. That's the kind of person you are.
你是走一步算一步的人
That's not the kind of person I am, okay?
我可不是这种人 明白吗？
You're responsible for the shitty decisions you've made.
你得为自己的烂决定承担后果
I never told you to get married, not once.
我可没逼你嫁人
- You cannot pawn them off onto me. - I understand.
- 别把你的烂摊子丢给我 - 我知道了
How much do you make a year at the pet store?
你在宠物店一年挣多少？
About $1200.
差不多1200块钱
Okay, in case you forgot, I have a week to make $1500,
别忘了 我一周内得弄到1500块
not including air fare.
还没算机票呢
I need to focus right now, no distractions.
现在必须专心 别让我分心
- I'm really sorry. - No, it's okay.
- 真的很抱歉 - 没事
It goes without saying, I'm in no position to settle down right now.
我不会和你安定下来的
Get that out of your mind. I will not settle down right now. Okay?
我现在没法跟你过日子 打消这个念头 明白吗？
If you're serious about leaving Ira, I will not abandon you.
要是你真打算离开艾勒 我不会丢下你
As your friend, I will help you.
作为朋友 我会帮你
We'll do the research, we'll find a great maternity home.
咱们打听打听 找个靠谱的产院收你
They'll take you in, they'll ensure the baby's got a good family.
孩子生了再找个好人家送走
We could do a-- No? No?
我们还能...不行吗？不行吗？
Then go home, Rachel. Just go home.
那就回家去吧 瑞秋 回家去吧
- What am I gonna say? - You'll figure it out. Go home, Rachel.
- 我该怎么跟他解释啊 - 自己想办法 快回去吧
Ira, wake up.
艾勒 醒醒
It's not your baby.
孩子不是你的
Stupid bitch, look at the fucking ground,
死贱人 不许抬头
like a dumb fucking whore.
臭婊子
Fuck.
去死吧
Fucking bullshit. Fucking go over there.
真他妈的 滚那边去
Stand in the fucking corner.
给我面壁去
I'm gonna smack... You wanna do this?
我要抽死你...想试试吗？
That baby's gonna be a pimple-faced bum just like its fucking father.
那野种肯定长成像他死爹那样的无赖
Or it's gonna be a whore like its fucking whore mother.
或者像她娘一样下贱
- Open up the door right now! - What?
- 快开门 - 又怎么了
There are people trying to sleep!
大半夜的还让不让人睡觉了
- Stop this! Quiet! - Hey, Rachel. It's your new mother-in-law.
- 够了 别闹了 - 瑞秋 快看 你的新婆婆来了
- Ira! Don't say that to her! - Hey, congratulations, Mrs. Mauser.
- 艾勒 别那样说她 - 恭喜你了 马蒂他妈
- You're gonna be a grandmother. - What?
- 你快要当奶奶了 - 什么？
Here, she's your problem now. Here, take her shit.
来 瑞秋现在是你的累赘了 拿好她的破烂
Rachel, do you need help?
瑞秋 需要帮忙吗？
- That's enough. Do you need help, honey? - I'm sorry.
- 别闹了 要帮忙吗？ - 对不起
- No, I'm okay. Everyone, go back to bed. - Yeah, great. She's so sorry.
- 我没事 大家都回去休息吧 - 她可会装可怜了
（劳伦斯百老汇球场）
【劳伦斯球场:20世纪中叶纽约著名乒乓球俱乐部】
- Are you Rachel? - You're Ezra?
- 你就是瑞秋吧 - 你是伊兹拉？
- Where is he? - Give me the money and I'll bring him out.
- 狗在哪儿？ - 先交钱 再交狗
Money? You ain't getting a nickel unless I see my dog.
先交钱？见不到狗 你一分钱也得不到
Just so you know, I'm not alone, okay? I got people watching all around me.
先说清楚 我有后援 一帮人看着呢
I don't give a shit who's watching.
我才他妈不管谁看着
I'm letting you know I'm very protected right now in case you try anything.
我被保护着 你别耍花样
- What? - Okay, do you want your dog?
- 什么？ - 好了 要狗吗？
I have your dog.
狗在我这里
- What are you doing? - I don't want that collar.
- 抢什么？ - 我不在乎项圈
- I want what's inside the collar. - Show me the money.
- 我要的是狗 - 把钱亮出来
Would I have this if I didn't have your dog? No.
要是我没你的狗 我哪会有这项圈？
So show me the money, and I'll go and get him for you.
把钱拿出来 我就去领狗
Come on. Come on!
快点 快点
You don't know who you're playing with, girl. Okay?
妹子 你知不知道你惹的是谁？
- Here's the money. - I don't fucking care.
- 这是钱 - 我才不管你是谁
Show me what's inside the envelope.
把信封打开
How am I supposed to know there's anything in there?
我怎么知道里面是不是钱
- Here, you wanna see? Here, look. Okay? - Yes. Great.
- 想看是吧？看清楚没？看清楚没？ - 行 挺好
- Where you going, girl? - Does she have the dog or what?
- 你往哪儿去？ - 她到底带没带狗来？
Who the fuck knows?
谁他妈知道
Okay.
好
- Yeah, Blarney Stone. - Hi, it's me.
- 喂 布拉尼斯通酒吧 - 喂 是我
Who's "me"?
你是谁？
Yeah, thank you. You can bring the dog out now.
好了 可以把狗牵出来了 谢谢
You're the one that left the dog? What happened to "coming right back"?
刚才把狗留这的是你？你说马上回来 这叫马上？
We're ready, so you can walk him outside.
都准备好了 牵出来吧
- The thing's pissed all over the floor. - Okay. I'll see you soon.
- 那畜生尿了一地 - 好的 待会儿见
- What is going on? - Listen to me for a second, okay?
- 怎么回事？ - 别急 听我说
Look. Right over there. Okay?
看 那边 瞧见没？
The green awning.
那个绿篷
My friend's gonna come out in a second with the dog.
我朋友马上会牵狗出来
Once you give me the money, I'm gonna call and say we're squared up, okay?
你先把钱给我 我打电话通报
Look, there he is right now with the dog. I told you.
瞧 牵着狗出来了 没骗你吧
So hand me the money.
把钱给我吧
Fuck you.
去你的
Hey! Hey, give me my money.
嘿 嘿 把钱给我
What about... Hey!
那我的钱呢 喂
Thief! Stop those two.
抓贼 拦住那两个人
- They took my wallet. - Hey.
- 他们抢了我的钱包 - 嘿
Stop them!
拦住他们
Where you going? Hey.
喂 别走
- Get off of me. - Come on.
- 滚开 松手 - 别跑了
Hey, him too! Him with the cast!
嘿 还有那个 那个打石膏的
With the cast.
那个打石膏的
What are you doing trying to steal from a pregnant woman?
竟然抢孕妇
- Shit. - Hey, police!
- 该死 - 快喊警察
What the fuck is this, man?
这他妈什么玩意儿？
That not Moses. Hey.
这不是摩西
That's not my dog.
这不是我的狗
- Where's my Moses? - Yo, I'm out here. The lady said to come here.
- 摩西在哪儿？有个女的叫我牵狗出来的
- Fucking playing games with me? - Stay away. Hey!
- 他妈的耍我是吧 - 别过来 喂
Fucking playing games with me? Huh?
他妈的耍我是吧
What kind of fucking shit you playing with me?
什么鬼把戏
- Hey, get the fuck off me. Back up, man. - Hey, calm down. Shit.
- 放手 滚开 退后 - 嘿 别激动 该死
- Shit. - Stop there.
- 糟了 - 站住
Someone help her!
快救她
- Somebody! Help! - I got you, you fucking bitch!
- 救命 救命啊 - 抓到你了 你这混蛋
Hey! Stop!
嘿 住手
What is it?
有事吗？
- Hey, how are you doing? - What are you doing here?
- 嘿 你好吗 - 你来这儿干什么？
It's 12:30. I was wondering if you wanted to get lunch.
都12点半了 要不要一起去吃个午饭？
It's out of the question. I have a show opening tonight.
不可能 今晚要首演
- Well, can I steal you away for an hour? - No.
- 能借你一小时吗？ - 不行
- Can I talk to you for a second? Please. - I'm very busy.
- 能跟你说句话吗？拜托 - 我很忙
Please, it'll just take a second.
就几句话 拜托了
- I feel kind of nervous telling you this. - What?
- 说实话我真的有点羞愧 - 怎么了？
All right, uh, I stole this from you, okay?
好吧 我承认 这是我偷的
And I want to return it. All right?
我想还给你
I'm sorry. My plan was to sell it and never see you again.
对不起 我本打算把它卖了 再也不见你
But I can't stop thinking about you, and I can't steal from you.
你住进我心里了 偷你的东西是不对的
Mmm.
哦
You know that's costume jewelry, right?
你知道那是假首饰吧？
- This is costume jewelry? I'm an idiot. - From the production.
- 假的？我真傻 - 演出道具
What happened to doing it all on your own? Where did that speech go?
你不是常说要靠自己吗 那话去哪儿了？
I know, I'm completely full of shit, okay?
那是装腔作势行了吧
I was in a tight spot, and I stole from you cause I needed some money,
我走投无路才偷了你的东西
and it was wrong.
我错了
I'm broke.
我穷得叮当响
Look, I got no resources.
我没门路
I got the championship next week in Japan. I got no way to get there.
下周要去日本打比赛 我连路费都没有
I got no options. I got no one looking out for me, Kay.
我没招了 没人能帮我 凯
Which isn't your problem. Which is why I'm returning it, okay?
当然 这不关你的事 我只是来还东西的
- You know what I think? - What?
- 你猜我怎么想吗？ - 怎么想？
- I think you went to sell that and discovered it was junk. - No.
- 你知道这是假货 卖不出去跑来装可怜 - 不是的
And now you've shown up here with this ridiculous strategy
还用这种蹩脚的把戏
to get me to have some sympathy and open my wallet.
想让我心软掏钱
That's absurd. You think I would insult your intelligence like that?
太荒唐了 我会这样侮辱你的智商吗？
- Are you gonna keep going? - Keep going what?
- 还没演够？ - 演什么？
- Are you gonna keep on with this? - Just being myself.
- 继续演这出戏 - 我在说实说啊
- You're lying through your teeth. - No, I'm not.
- 你满嘴谎话 - 才没有
- It's me being me. - This is pathetic. You're being you?
- 我的诚实写在脸上 - 你到底还有没有脸？
I am telling you the truth.
我说的可是实话
I stole from you and then I feel bad about it,
我偷了 然后很后悔很内疚
- so I'm trying to make amends. - You're wasting your energy. I don't care.
- 所以我来弥补 - 省省吧 我才不在乎
I would have stolen from me too.
换成我也会偷的
Kay.
凯
- Hi. - Looks like I'm interrupting something.
- 嗨 - 打断你们了吧
No, no. Not at all.
没事 没事
This is Martin, my friend Carol's son. He was just leaving.
这是马丁 我朋友卡萝的儿子 他正要走
- This is Merle, my publicist. - Hello.
- 这位是默尔 我的宣传人 - 你好
Martin would like to be an actor, but unfortunately he's not very good.
马丁想当演员 可惜演技不怎么样
Ah, well, you know, Broadway needs ushers too.
在百老汇当个门童也挺好的
So what's happening with the seating?
座位安排的怎么样了？
I spoke to Milton. He's sending all of his employees.
我跟米尔顿谈过了 他会派全体职工来
It's like a mandate. Like, a company mandate.
算是公司总动员了
This is supposed to make me happy?
就这样糊弄我吗？
Well, I mean, it's a full house. Isn't that the point?
不是说要座无虚席吗？
Full of fucking morons. - No, no. You got some--
全是不识货的 - 不 不是的
- Fred Astaire is coming. - Okay, I'm gonna get out your hair...
- 弗雷德·阿斯泰尔也会来 - 我先走了 不打扰你们了
【弗雷德·阿斯泰尔:20世纪美国著名舞者和演员】
No. Make sure you give him a ticket for tonight.
别急着走 记得给他留张今晚的票
- Really? - Yeah.
- 给我？ - 对
Oh. You are in for such a treat, young man.
小伙子 你这下有福了
When you see this lady act,
你看她演一回就知道
you're gonna feel like you got your cock sucked by a vacuum cleaner.
什么叫千秋难得一见 吸引四海八荒了
- Merle! - She's blushing. See her?
- 默尔 - 她脸红了 看见没？
What?
说什么呢
（莫罗斯科剧院票 持票人马蒂·毛瑟）
（马蒂 午夜到中央公园来见我 靠近第五大道960号那边 凯）
Take your stinking seat.
坐好别乱动
What the hell?
怎么回事？
Have you lost your damned mind?
你发什么神经？
Jed. I'm talking to you.
小杰 我在跟你说话呢
I was just practicing my aim, Mama.
妈 我只是练练枪法
You always said to shoot for the stars.
你不一直催我找准目标吗？
Hey.
嘿
Come.
跟我走
I'm sorry I'm late. I couldn't get away.
抱歉我来晚了 脱不开身
- Oh, I bet. - He was all over me.
- 呵 我信你 - 他一直缠着我
You were incredible tonight. That was unbelievable.
你今晚演得棒极了 太精彩了
- I have something for you. - For me?
- 我有样东西给你 - 给我？
Turn around.
转过去
Every year my husband gives me a piece of jewelry for our anniversary.
每周年我丈夫都会送我一件首饰
I have 25 of them. One for each year of misery.
我有25件了 每件都代表受了一年的苦
That should cover your trip and then some.
这条够你那趟路费了 没准还能剩
Wearing it makes me feel like shit.
戴着让我浑身不自在
Oh, shit. Stop, stop, stop.
完了 停下 停下 停下
Stop.
停
Hey! Hey, what are you doing?
喂 喂 你们在干什么呢？
- Shit. Oh, God. - Get up!
- 完了 天呐 - 站起来
- Lay still. - Stand up, I see you.
- 躺着别动 - 我看见你们了 站起来
When I tell you, run. One, two, three. Get up.
我数到三就跑 一 二 三 起来
- Come on. Go. - Hey!
- 快走 走 - 嘿
Joey, stop them!
乔伊 拦住他们
Come on. Come on. Come on.
快走 快走 快走
Hey. Hey. Where are you guys going? What are you guys doing here?
嘿 你们往哪儿去？跑这儿干嘛呢？
- Nothing. - No, no, no.
- 没干嘛 - 不 不 不
- Let me see both of your hands. - Cuff him.
- 把手举起来 - 铐上那小子
- Oh, my God. We were just... - We didn't do anything.
- 天呐 我们只是... - 我们什么都没干
Give us a break. We were looking for her earrings in the grass.
饶了我们吧 我们只是在草地上找她的耳环
My earring came off. We were looking for my earring.
我的耳环掉了 只是在耳环
It looks like you've got two earrings in your ears there.
你耳朵上不是戴了两只耳环吗
Not this earring. There was... From before. There was another earring.
不是这只 不是刚才掉的 还有一只
There's another pair of earrings from earlier in the day.
白天还丢过另一对耳环
I recognize you.
我认出你了
- Oh, God. Oh, God. - You're Kay Stone.
- 天呐 天呐 - 你是凯·斯通
- Yes. I know exactly who you are. - This is not happening.
- 没错 我太清楚你是谁了 - 见鬼了
- Let see your hands. - Are you serious?
- 把手给我 - 你认真的吗？
You know, I will go home,
这样吧 我回家取个钱包
and I'll get my wallet, and I will get you some cash
给你们些钱赔偿
because we've put you out.
毕竟给你们添麻烦了
Please, officer. She's gonna go home and get her wallet. And give you cash.
请你行行好 警官 她这就回家拿钱包 给你们现金
- Got ID? - No. No ID.
- 有证件吗？ - 没 没证件
- Cuff her. - No, please.
- 把她也铐上 - 不要 求你了
- No ID, huh? Let's see. - Please, please. No, no, no.
- 没证是吧？让我搜搜 - 求你了 求你了
- Please, will you just let me go home? - Come on.
- 求你了 让我回家拿钱包吧 - 求你了
I'll give you my word.
我向你保证
Wow, lookie here. That's a really nice necklace.
哇 瞧瞧 这项链可真漂亮啊
Take it. Take it. It's yours.
拿去 拿去吧 归你了
Thank you very much.
那我就不客气了
I can't believe this.
真不敢相信
Do you think you could grab me another necklace?
能再拿条项链给我吗？
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
You said them mean nothing to you. It'd just take you a couple of minutes.
你不是说这项链对你没价值吗 就几分钟的事
I was just gone for half an hour. I can't go up and come right back down.
我都消失了半小时 不能进去又立刻出来
- You'd do that for the police officers. - My mother is up there.
- 你给警察倒是挺爽快的啊 - 我妈就在屋里
- Oh, my God. My hair. - I'll wait in the hall.
- 天呐 我的头发都乱了 - 我在走廊等你
No, you will not.
不 不准跟来
Wait. Wait.
等等 等等
There.
好了
You look beautiful.
你真漂亮
Please, you have 25 of them.
求你了 你有25条呢
Fine!
好
- Stay here. Do you understand me? - I'll stay here. Okay.
- 待在这儿 明白吗？ - 好 我就在这里等
- Do not move. - Okay.
- 别乱跑 - 好
Shit.
倒霉
Hello. Lovely to see you.
你好 很高兴见到你们
- David, how are you? - Good. How are you?
- 大卫 你好吗？ - 挺好 你呢？
Where the fuck have you been?
你死哪去了？
I needed a moment to myself. Is that a problem?
我出去透透气 有意见吗？
I didn't realize I needed a permission slip.
出门还得请示吗？
I put this whole thing on for you and you're making me look like an idiot.
我为你操办了这一切 你现在却让我丢面子
God.
天呐
Look. Merle's on the phone right now with The New York Times.
听着 默尔已经跟《纽约时报》那边联系上了
- What? - He's got a printer who's gonna read the review.
- 真的假的？ - 他找到个能念出明天剧评的人
My God.
天呐
- Or do you not care? - I got him! I have him!
- 你在乎不在乎？ - 找着他了 我找着他了
- Oh, my God. Okay. - Come, come, come!
- 天呐 来了 - 快来 快来
Coming!
来了
- Hurry, he has the review! - I'm coming.
- 快点 拿到剧评了 - 来了
The review!
剧评出来了
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
快点 快点 快点
- Come on, come on. - Okay.
- 快来 - 来了
Raoul, Kay.
这是拉乌尔 她是凯
Okay. Title, "Kay Stone Returns" by Robert...
好 标题是《凯·斯通复出》 作者罗伯特...
- Have a good night. - Leave it open. Everyone's coming down.
- 晚安 - 别关门 大家都要下来了
- Are they? - Oh, yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是的
Party's over.
庆祝会结束了
Good night.
晚安
The party's over.
庆祝会结束了
- They're asking us to leave. - What do you mean? We just got here.
- 他们说散场了 - 什么意思？咱们才刚到啊
They should've stopped us at the door. Why'd they let us in?
怎么门口不拦还让我们进？
It's done, the party's gone.
完了 聚会没了
Excuse me. Do you know where Kay is?
打扰下 请问凯在哪儿？
- She's upstairs in her bedroom. - Okay.
- 她在楼上卧室里 - 好的
Hi. Is Kay in there?
嗨 凯在屋里吗？
This is not a good time.
现在不方便
Okay, but can I just speak to her?
明白 能让我跟她说下吗
As I said, it's really not a good time.
我都说了 现在真不方便
At the end of the year, if the guy made you money, you keep him.
年底结账 能赚钱的就留着
And if not, you throw the bum out.
不赚钱的就踢出去呗
Excuse me.
打扰下
- Hi. - You gotta be kidding me.
- 您好 - 开啥玩笑啊
- I'm sorry to disturb you in your home. - How did you fuck get in my house?
- 抱歉登门打扰了 - 你怎么混进我家的？
Please give me another chance. I am on my hands and knees.
求您再给我一次机会 我求您了
I need a ride to Japan and I need $1,500 so I can compete in the championship.
我得去日本 还需要1500块才能参加世锦赛
I need this job very, very badly.
这活对我太重要了
I'm begging you.
我求您了
I'll work for you however you want. I will lose.
我完全听您安排 输球也行
I'll have no personal point of view apart from making your event a success.
我唯一目标就是把您的活动办成功
Marty, there are no second chances in life.
马蒂 人生没有第二次机会
- Why not? - I offered you the job and you said no!
- 为什么不行？ - 我给过你机会 你当时拒绝了
I know, because I was impulsive. And I regret it.
我知道 我当时太冲动了 我很后悔
And?
除了后悔呢？
And I was rude and overconfident.
我还没礼貌 还自负
And I was cocky, and I copped an attitude.
我得意忘形 还耍架子
And?
还有呢？
And it won't happen again. I'm sorry.
我保证不会再犯了 对不起
Please just give me another chance, Mr. Rockwell.
求您再给我一回机会 罗克韦尔先生
I'm throwing myself at your mercy. I'll do whatever you want.
我任您发落 您吩咐什么我就做什么
What do you guys think? Should I give this little asshole a second chance?
你们怎么看？该给这小混蛋一次机会吗？
- Yes, please! - Don't ask me.
- 是的 求您了 - 别问我
You don't know how important this is to me. Please. I'm begging you.
这对我太重要了 求求您了
Just let me go on your plane, and let me join you there.
求您让我跟您上飞机去日本
Please, I'm humbling myself before you.
求求您了 我正跪着求您
- You're making me sick. - I'm sorry.
- 你这副模样真恶心 - 对不起
- Stand up! - Okay. All right.
- 站起来! - 好的 行
Please. Okay? I'll do anything.
求您了 让我做什么都行
- Anything? - Yes. Anything.
- 什么都行？ - 对 什么都行
Okay.
好
Go down the hall. Second door on the right is my office.
顺着走廊走 右手边第二间是我办公室
Grab the paddle and bring it back here.
去把球拍拿来
This is more dramatic than the play.
这要比刚才那出戏还精彩了
- Okay. - That's true.
- 好的 - 可不是吗
（罗克韦尔墨业）
Oh, Marty. Give me the paddle.
马蒂 把球拍给我
So here's what I want you to do.
照我说的做
I want you to bend over that chair and drop your pants.
我要你趴那椅子上 把裤子脱了
Are you for real?
你认真的吗？
You've been a really bad boy. Now you're gonna get a spanking.
你这小子调皮过头了 得好好打屁股了
Come on. Are you serious?
别这样 你认真的吗？
You wanna get to Japan, don't you?
想去日本吗？
Yeah, I wanna go to Japan. But this is what you want?
是的 我想去日本 可这真是你想要的？
That's what it's gonna take. Now bend over.
这就是代价 趴好
Okay, so to be clear,
好吧 先说好
you're gonna bring me to Japan and then you're gonna compensate me?
你会带我去日本 然后还给我钱吗？
Tomorrow morning, 8:30, LaGuardia. We're on our way to Japan.
明早八点半 拉瓜迪亚机场 我们就动身去日本
- Do I need a ticket? - I own the plane.
- 还要买票吗？ - 飞机是我的
How do I know you're gonna honor this?
我怎么知道你说话算数？
You don't. Because you have no power here.
你不知道 你没资格跟我讨价还价
Now bend over.
趴好
Put your hands over here. I want a nice arc.
手放这儿 弧度要漂亮点
Let's go.
趴好
Oh, my God.
噢 天呐
Okay, I'm ready.
行了 我准备好了
This one is for my son.
这一下是替我儿子打的
Okay.
好
This one is for me.
这一下是给我解气的
God!
哎呦
Now the bonus round.
下面是加赛环节
Beautiful paddle. One side's wood and the other is foam.
多好的球拍 一面是木头 一面是海绵
- Hey, Marty, how you doin'? - Hey, Ted. Hey, Lawrence.
- 嘿 马蒂 怎么样？ - 你好 泰德 你好 劳伦斯
Aw, damn. Hey, man. How you doin'?
嘿 近来可好？
You think I could stay in the back room tonight?
你看我今晚能住后屋吗？
- Wow, man. I got Brian staying there tonight. - I get it. All right.
- 真不巧 后屋今晚给布赖恩了 - 好吧
I would let you stay at the house, man, but the wife ain't havin' it.
我真想让你到我家歇 但我老婆不答应
No, It's all right. I'm just gonna hang around until my flight.
没事 我就在这儿晃悠到起飞吧
Where you goin'?
你要去哪?
Going to Japan. Tomorrow morning, 8:00 a.m.
去日本 明早八点出发
- Oh, yeah! - My man!
- 太好了 - 好样的小伙子
- Yo, you goin'! You got that money. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 哟 你真要去啦 弄到钱了 - 是啊 是啊
Good for you, man.
祝贺你 小伙计
You ain't even look like you excited.
你表情怎么这么沉啊
No, I'm-- I'm good. I'm good.
没事 我...挺好的 我挺好的
You know your boy back there, Wally, he's been waitin' on you.
你那哥们沃利在后头 他一直在等你
- Wally's here? - Wally, yeah.
- 沃利在这儿吗？ - 沃利在啊
- How'd he seem? - Wally's good. He cool, man.
- 他怎么样？ - 沃利挺好 挺淡定的 伙计
He's back there somewhere.
他就在里面
- He believes in you. - He has a dollar. She has a dollar.
- 他很看好你 - 当时大家都在掏钱
Hey. How you doing?
嘿 你好
Oh, wow! How you doing? Nice to see you!
噢 哇 见到你真好
I've been trying to get in touch with you.
我一直想联系你
- Oh, really? - Yeah. How's your dog? How's Moses doing?
- 真的？ - 是啊 你家狗怎样了 摩西怎么样？
You wanna cut the bullshit?
你能别扯了吗？
No bullshit. I'm genuinely concerned about him.
没胡扯 我是真关心那狗的
- Marty, Marty, Marty. You good, man? - Yeah, I'm good.
- 马蒂 马蒂 有麻烦吗？ - 没事 没事
Now, listen to me. Listen. Listen. Listen.
听着 听着 听着
I got your girl downstairs in the car. She's waiting for you.
你那小妞就在楼下车里 她正等你呢
What the fuck are you telling me? You got Rachel?
你扯什么呢？你抓了瑞秋？
Yeah.
对
She told me my dog's in Jersey somewhere. And you got the address.
她跟我说狗在新泽西某处 你知道地址
- Okay. - Let's go.
- 好 - 咱们走
Okay. All right. Let me, uh...
行吧 好吧 让我...
Um, okay, let me just...
额 行吧 让我先...
Give me two seconds. I just wanna say one thing to my friend.
给我两秒钟 我就跟我哥们说句话
Give you two seconds, yeah, but I'm not gonna be here.
给你两秒钟行 但老子可不等你
- Where you gonna be? - Where am I gonna be?
- 不等我你干嘛？ - 我干嘛？
I'm gonna be downstairs taking a hammer to your girl's stomach.
我这就下楼用锤子敲烂她那肚子
That's where I'm gonna be.
这就是我要干的事
Okay. All right. All right.
好 好 好
Yo, Mouse!
喂 小毛毛
- Come on. Let's go. - Okay.
- 走 别磨蹭 - 好吧
Well, I took most of his share of the money that our parents left us.
他的遗产大部分也被我拿了
- You spent your brother's money? - Yes, I did.
- 你拿了你弟那份？ - 是的
Yeah, you love your brother?
呵 看来你挺疼你弟的
Yeah. Maybe you could give my brother a job. You know he's a good man.
疼啊 要不你给我弟安排个差事 他人不错
I'll give him your job, okay? Mitch, do me a favor.
让他取代你 行了吧？米奇 帮个忙
What?
干嘛？
Stop talking. Okay?
闭嘴 行吗？
Okay. See the gas station there?
好了 看到那加油站没？
it's the house to the left.
往左那个房子就是
- Next left? - Yeah.
- 前面左转？ - 对
I got it.
知道了
Get out of the car. Come on.
下车 赶紧的
Mitch, come.
米奇 下来
- Reuben, you wait with her. - Oh, okay.
- 鲁本 你留下看着她 - 好的
Sit tight.
老实坐着
Come on. Louder.
快点 使劲敲
Knock louder.
使劲敲
That's my dog.
那是我的狗
Moses! Yo!
摩西 喂
Open up!
赶紧开门
Fuck. Moses.
真黑 摩西
- Come on. - I hate that fuckin' mutt.
- 开门 - 我讨厌死那狗了
Moses!
摩西
That's my dog. Moses!
那是我的狗 摩西
Moses!
摩西
See anything in there?
里头看见啥没？
No, not really.
没 没看到什么
- Marty! - Shit.
- 马蒂 - 该死
Marty! Go!
马蒂 快跑
Marty!
马蒂
Get down! Get down!
趴下 趴下
Fuck!
该死
Marty! Marty! I got shot!
马蒂 马蒂 我中弹了
Help!
救命
Help, Marty! Please help!
救命 马蒂 快帮帮我
Help!
帮帮我
Are you okay? Oh, no! Are you okay?
你没事吧？噢不 你没事吧？
- Are you okay? - What the fuck's going on?
- 你没事吧？ - 这他妈是怎么回事？
Okay. It's okay.
好了 没事的
I'm bleeding, I'm bleeding.
我流血了 流血了
Okay. It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
好了 没事的 没事的 没事的
- I'm so sorry. - I'm sorry.
- 真对不起 - 对不起
- Go get the money. - What money?
- 快去拿钱 - 什么钱？
Go get the money. It's in his pocket. It's in his pocket.
快去拿钱 就在他口袋里 在他兜里
Are you sure?
你确定？
- The money! It's in the inside pocket! - Okay, okay, okay.
- 钱 就在他口袋里 - 好的 知道了 知道了
Oh, fuck.
该死
What is this?
这都是什么啊
Oh, you motherfucker...
噢 你个王八蛋...
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
好了 好了 没事了 没事了
Fuck!
该死
Get off me! Where do you think you're going?
放手 你要去哪儿？
it's okay.
没事的
Okay.
好了
- You got it? You got it? - Yeah. I got it, I got it.
- 拿到了吗？拿到了吗？ - 嗯 拿到了 拿到了
- You got the money? - Yeah. I got it, I got it.
- 钱拿到了吗？ - 嗯 拿到了 拿到了
- Is there a lot of money? - There's a lot.
- 钱多吗？ - 很多 很多
- You can go now. - I know. You did amazing.
- 你能去日本了 - 我知道 你做得真棒
- You can go on your trip now. - I knew you could do this. So good.
- 你可以去参赛了 - 我就知道你行 太棒了
You did such a good job.
你帮了大忙
I love you.
我爱你
- Honey, when is your due date? - Why? Is the baby okay?
- 你预产期什么时候？ - 怎么了？孩子没事吧？
The baby is fine. I just need you to calm down.
孩子没事 你得冷静下来
- Are you the husband? - No. I'm her friend.
- 你是她丈夫吗？ - 不是 我是她朋友
She's due in four weeks. The baby will be okay?
她还有四周就生 孩子会没事吧？
The baby is okay. It's time to say goodbye.
孩子没事 你不能进了
- I can't go? - Only family in the operating room.
- 我不能进？ - 手术室只允许家属进去
No, no, no, no, no!
不 不 不 不 不
It's gonna be fine. Rachel, it's fine. It's fine.
会没事的 瑞秋 都会没事的 放心
No, no, no! Marty, no.
不 不 不 马蒂 别走
He'll be right outside.
他就在外面等着
Marty, no!
马蒂 别走
Rachel, I can't go. They're telling me I can't go.
瑞秋 我进不去 他们不让我进
- I don't want you to-- - Please calm down.
- 我不想让你... - 冷静下来
- Marty, don't go, please! - Please try calm down.
- 马蒂 别走 求你别走 - 冷静点
Please don't go! Marty!
求你别走 马蒂
No!
不要
Thank you very much. Welcome to Japan, Mr. Rockwell.
罗克韦尔先生 欢迎来到日本 祝您愉快
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
（行李领取处）
（日本 东京）
（罗克韦尔 原子笔）
（日语）好了 下一轮比赛
（日语）马上就要开始了
（赢一分 得一笔）
（远藤加油 争创佳绩）
（用罗克韦尔书写传奇）
- （日语）这位挑战者是早川先生 大家掌声欢迎
- （日语）远藤加油
（日语）你有信心吗？
（日语）有
（日语）加油 加油
（日语）让我们拭目以待
（日语）那么接下来有请
（日语）远藤出场
（世界第二 马蒂·毛瑟 最终落败）
（日语）有点可惜
- （日语）远藤加油
- （日语）下面请下一位挑战者上场
Mr. Mauser. Mr. Mauser.
毛瑟先生 毛瑟先生
Ah. Mr. Rockwell says the back of the line.
罗克韦尔说让你排到最后
He doesn't want to begin yet.
他还不想让你上场
（挑战者在此排队）
（日语）这位才11岁...
（世锦赛售票处）
（日语）谢谢
- Practice beer "biiru". - Okay, kanpai.
- 跟我学 日语管啤酒叫“比鲁” - 来 干杯
Mr. Sethi? Mr. Sethi.
塞西先生 塞西先生
Hey. It's me. It's Marty Mauser.
嘿 是我 马蒂·毛瑟
How you doing? I'm surprised to see you here, actually.
你好啊 真没想到能在这碰到您
- Why's that? - I don't know. I--
- 此话怎讲？ - 我不知道 我...
We do have a tournament to promote.
我们来这里宣传锦标赛
No, of course, of course.
嗯 当然 当然
Yeah.
好吧
I think I owe you an apology for the way I acted in London.
我想给您道个歉 伦敦的事
I was a jackass.
那确实不像话
There is such a thing as a code of courtesy, Mr. Mauser.
做人要有分寸 毛瑟先生
No, I know, I know. It's just--
对 我知道 我知道 只是...
It's every man for himself where I come from.
我出身的环境
That's just how I grew up. Okay?
为了混口饭谁都不讲究 懂吗？
And sometimes I feel like I don't even have control--
有时候我老毛病也会犯...
I'm really not interested in your excuses.
我不想听这些借口
No, no, I know. It's not an excuse.
不 不 知道 这不是借口
Look, the point is I'm gonna proceed with a much better attitude.
我会改掉那些做派
And by the way, if you see me acting rude up there today,
要是今天我上台表现粗鲁
that's a character. This is scripted. I'm gonna lose 21-14.
那是演的 事先安排好的 我会以21比14输掉
This isn't a real thing. The real me, the polite me, you'll see next week.
这不代表我 下周赛场上你们会看到规规矩矩的我
- Next week? - At the championship.
- 下周？ - 世锦赛上
You're not playing in the championship.
世锦赛跟你没关系
- What? - You're not participating this year.
- 什么？ - 你今年被禁赛了
No, no, no. I think you're confused.
不 不 不 您搞错了
That's what I'm doing the event for, so I can pay off the rest of my fine.
我就是借这活动来凑齐罚款的
Come talk to Mr. Rockwell right now.
跟我去找罗克韦尔谈谈
The tournament is less than two weeks away.
比赛还有不到两周就开始了
- All the bracketing has been set. - No, but we'll redo the bracketing.
- 对阵表都排好了 - 不 咱们可以重排
I'm not gonna tear up the entire schedule on behalf of one entitled American.
我不会为个自以为是的美国人把整个安排打乱
No, Mr. Sethi. Mr. Sethi. Look...
不 塞西先生 塞西先生 你看...
I'm here.
我已经来了
I don't think you know how difficult that was, for me to come here.
我千里迢迢赶来的 您根本想象不到有多难
I'm in Japan right now.
我现在可真到日本了
You haven't come far enough, I'm afraid.
恐怕你走得还不够远
- What? - You have wasted your time coming here.
- 什么意思？ - 你来这儿就是徒劳
This is unbelievable.
真荒唐啊
（日语）来看看这位挑战者
（远藤加油 争创佳绩）
（罗克韦尔墨业）
（用罗克韦尔书写传奇）
（日语）哎呀 真可惜啊
（日语）请两位选手互相握手
（日语）友谊第一 比赛第二
- （日语）下面请出下一位挑战者
- （日语）下一位
（日语）请站到这里来
（日语）请问您叫什么名字？
（日语）哎呦
（日语）太意外了
（世界第二 马蒂·毛瑟 最终落败）
（日语）他是马蒂·毛瑟 美国的顶尖选手
（日语）大家掌声欢迎
I've traveled many miles here to Japan
我千里迢迢跑到日本
to challenge my great nemesis, Endo!
就是为了挑战我的死对头远藤
Come on, Marty!
加油 马蒂
（日语）你要怎么做 远藤选手？
What's he say?
他说什么？
He doesn't want to embarrass you anymore.
他不想让你再丢脸了
Embarrass me? I am beyond embarrassment.
让我丢脸？我的脸早没了
Tell him he's a-- Your champion is a fraud and a chicken.
跟他说...你们的冠军就是个冒牌货 还是个怂包
He's chicken!
他就是个怂包
Mr. Endo agrees to the match.
远藤先生同意比赛
Great.
很好
On the condition that...
不过有个条件...
the loser has to kiss a pig in front of the entire audience.
输的人得当着全场观众亲一头猪
- A pig? - Yes.
- 亲猪？ - 是的
A pig? What?
亲猪？开什么玩笑？
He said if you are going to act like a pig,
他说你要是摆出猪样
he will happily mate you with one.
他很乐意帮你配个种
What does that--
这话什么意...
（日语）大家或许没听懂
（日语）输了的人要当众亲一头猪
（日语）现在比分19比14
（日语）轮到远藤发球
（日语）这一球至关重要
（日语）毛瑟已经走投无路了
（日语）好险
It's this cord in the fucking way.
这根该死的电线绊着我了
I'm stepping on the cord. Move the cord.
- 绊着我了 把线挪开 - （日语）他说输是被电线害的
Move the cord over there so I don't slip on it next time!
快把线挪走 别害的我再被绊倒
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - So I don't break my ankle!
- 对不起 对不起 - 我可不想被绊倒摔断腿
（日语）20比14 远藤的赛点
（日语）决定性一球
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）比赛结束
（日语）胜负已分
（日语）本场获胜的是...
（日语）更强的远藤选手
（日语）请给他热烈掌声
（日语）这场比赛真是激烈
（日语）不过好戏还在后头
（日语） 现在有请一位特邀嘉宾上台
- You speak English? - Yeah.
- 你会说英语吗？ - 会
What's he saying?
他在说什么？
"We are welcoming a special guest."
“有请一位特邀嘉宾上台”
"Mr. Ram Sethi. Come on up."
“有请 拉姆·塞西先生”
Thank you.
谢谢大家
And thank you, Mr. Rockwell, for hosting such an unforgettable event.
同时感谢罗克韦尔先生主办这场难忘的盛会
What we have just witnessed is a mere taste of what is to come next week
刚才不过是下周精彩对决的开胃菜
when the finest players in the world will be competing
下周世界顶尖选手将与
against your hometown hero, Koto Endo-san.
你们的英雄远藤功人一较高下
（日语）远藤加油
（日语）可一定要赢
No more words from me. Let's bring on Agu the pig
我就不多说了 现在请小猪阿古上台
and see the American plant a kiss on him.
让这位美国人来个亲猪表演
"Now we bring the pig onto the stage."
“现在把猪请上台”
Wait, wait, wait.
等一下 等一下 等一下
Hey. Hey.
嘿 嘿
I want to play him in a real game first before I kiss the pig.
我要求先打一场真比赛 然后再亲猪
I want to play him in a real game.
打一场真刀真枪的比赛
Tell him I want to play him in a game that's not a sham.
告诉他 我想来场不掺水的比赛
Tell him!
告诉他
You, tell the audience that was a fake game, and was a sham.
你 告诉观众 刚才是假的 掺水的
Tell them it was a sham and I want to play a real game against him.
告诉他们是在演戏 我想跟他来场真的
- I cannot do that for you. - Why can't you do that?
- 我不能说 - 凭什么不能？
That was a fake game. That was staged.
刚才是场假比赛 是提前安排好的
No part of that was real.
没一点是真的
I was not playing to the best of my ability.
我根本没拿出实力来
It was an enormous form of disrespect to everyone here.
这是对大家的侮辱
Hey, listen, who wants a real game?
大家听着 你们想不想看真比赛？
Show of hands. Come on.
要看真比赛的举个手 举手
Wait, this man. This man.
等等 有人举手 有人举手
（日语）要打就真打
Marty, you're right. We want to see the real game!
马蒂 你说得对 我们要看真比赛
Yes!
太好了
（日语）要真打
En-do, you're gonna side with them?
远藤 你要跟他们同流合污吗？
Translate. Translate this.
翻译 赶快翻译这句
He's gonna side with them, really?
问他要跟他们同流合污吗？
An American company selling their product off of his back like he's a mascot?
问他是不是真想给美国公司当摆设？
You're not a mascot.
你又不是人家的玩物
- Brian, get him down. - You can throw that 'cause you're the winner.
- 布莱恩 把他弄走 - 你是冠军你有权
Let's give them a real game. They want a real game.
咱们来场真的 观众想看真比赛
Okay, okay.
行了行了
Thank you, thank you. We need to move it along.
谢谢 谢谢 该下一个环节了
I'm not gonna be at the championship next week
我下周没法去打世锦赛
'cause of this asshole. I'm not gonna be at the championship.
就是因为这混蛋作梗 我去不了了
Give me a chance. You humiliated me. You roasted me.
给我个机会 你已经让我丢脸了 丢大脸了
Please, please, Endo. Please.
求你了 求你了 远藤 求你
- Please, for me. Yes? - Okay.
- 拜托了 就当帮我 行吗？ - 好吧
- Yes. Okay. - Good? He says yes?
- 好 他同意了 - 好？他答应了？
He says yes.
他同意了
Thank you, Endo. Thank you.
谢谢你 远藤 谢谢
He said yes. Yes.
他答应了 太好了
（日语）想不到
（日语）比赛竟然还要继续
（日语）欢呼过后 比赛再度开打
（日语）远藤再度对决
（日语）美国选手马蒂·毛瑟
This little fuck.
- （日语）两位冠军的真刀真枪对决现在开始 - 这小畜生
Let's do this.
明白
（日语）远藤先发球
（日语）比赛开打
Fuck.
该死
（日语）太好了
（日语）远藤 得分
（日语）1比0
Okay, Marty. All right.
马蒂 振作起来
Don't let him beat you, Marty.
别输给他 马蒂
（日语）拉锯战开始了
（日语）远藤好样的
（远藤加油）
（日语）又得一分
（日语）2比0
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）毛瑟也不甘示弱
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟 得分
（日语）远藤领先只剩一分
（日语）比分2比1
Yeah!
- （日语） 马蒂·毛瑟 再次得分 - 太好了
Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
- （日语）目前比分2比2 平局 - 加油 马蒂 加油 小伙子
（日语）毛瑟毫不退让
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）现在轮到毛瑟发球
（日语）远藤和马蒂都在全力以赴
（日语）现在比分是17比17 平局
（日语）比赛已经白热化
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟 得分
（日语）远藤失分了
（日语）被对手追上来了
（日语）追上来了一分
（日语）毛瑟领先一分
（日语）现在比分是18比17
- （日语）这才是真正的对决 大家给点掌声加油吧
- （日语）借过 借过
You can save your breath. I know I'm not getting paid.
省省吧 我知道钱没戏了
Win or lose, you get nothing. I wonder how you're gonna get home.
赢不赢都别想拿到钱 我倒是好奇你怎么回家
- You're not getting on my plane. - It doesn't matter, okay?
- 你别想坐我的飞机 - 无所谓
Unless you're planning on shutting down the event, we got nothing to discuss.
除非你打算叫停这活动 否则没有什么好说的
- You think it's that simple? - Yeah, I do.
- 你真觉得这么简单吗？ - 对 我就这么觉得
Let me explain to you.
我来给你讲明白
I was born in 1601. I'm a vampire. I've been around forever.
我生在1601年 是个吸血鬼 我活得太久了
I've met many Marty Mausers over the centuries.
我见过太多像你这样的马蒂
Some of them crossed me, some weren't straight. They weren't honest.
有人顶撞过我 有人不守规矩
And those are the ones that are still here.
而那些人我让他们永远受罪
You go out and win that game, you're gonna be here forever too.
你要是赢了 我会让你永远受罪
And you'll never be happy. You will never be happy.
让你求生不得 求死不能
All right.
好吧
Okay, Mr. Rockwell.
好了 罗克韦尔先生
（日语）休息结束 比赛继续
（日语）目前比分18比17
（日语）毛瑟领先一分
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）现在由远藤发球
（日语）开局不错
（日语）又是一轮拉锯战
（日语）漂亮
（日语）远藤 得一分
（日语）远藤终于把比分扳平
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）欢呼声越来越响亮了
（日语）目前比分是18比18
（日语）精彩继续
There we go!
来吧
（日语）可惜了 毛瑟得分
（日语）现在比分19比18
（日语）毛瑟毫不让步
（日语）又要发球了
（日语）打过去了
（日语）又被打回来了
（日语）打回去了
（日语）这球...远藤进攻成功
（日语）远藤又追平了
（日语）比分19比19
（日语）现场气氛越来越热闹了
（日语）比赛继续
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）击出
（日语）接得好
（日语）打得好
（日语）太精彩了
（日语）太惊心动魄了
（日语）20比19
（日语）远藤到达了赛点
（日语）日本观众们 一起为他加油吧
（日语）进入赛点 比赛更紧张精彩了
Match point.
- （日语） 远藤能再得一分吗？ - 到赛点了
（日语）大家拭目以待
（日语）远藤必胜
（日语）加油吧 毛瑟
（日语）加油吧
（日语）能接住吗？
（日语）仍在僵持
（日语）又是猛攻
（日语）天呐
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）再次得分
（日语）再次扳回比分的是马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）20比20
（日语）20分后 远藤必须连拿两分才能获胜
（日语）现在由毛瑟发球
（日语）球差点擦网
（日语）双方都在用正手击球
（日语）现在换到反手了
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟正手得分
（日语）毛瑟拿到赛点
（日语）双方你追我赶
（日语）日本观众陷入了沉默
（日语）马蒂只要一分就能战胜远藤
（日语）远藤被逼到了绝境
（日语）毛瑟能撑住吗？
（日语）毛瑟撑住就能赢
（日语）接下来会发生什么？
- Don't let him getcha, Marty! - Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
- 别输给他 马蒂 - 马蒂 加油 加油
（日语）这是最后一球吗？
（日语）谁能笑到最后？
（日语）是毛瑟还是远藤？
（日语）最后一局了
（日语）远藤能撑住吗？
（日语）别眨眼
（日语）拉锯战又开始了
（日语）远藤处于劣势
（日语）要是毛瑟得分 远藤就输了
（日语）打回去了
（日语）打得异常激烈
（日语）胜负已分
（日语）获胜者是马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）精彩的对决
（日语）多么精彩的致胜一击
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟创造了历史
Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you. Good game. Good game.
谢谢你 打得好 打得好
You're a great player.
你真是个可敬的对手
Good luck at the championship, okay? I hope you win.
世锦赛你一定要加油 我真心希望你赢
（日语）本场比赛获胜者是马蒂·毛瑟
Bellevue Hospital. May I help you?
贝尔维尤医院 有什么可以帮您？
Hi, yes.
喂 是的
I was hoping to be connected with Rachel Mizler, please?
请帮我转接瑞秋·米兹勒 谢谢
Do you know what floor she's on?
请问她在几楼？
Well, she would have gotten out of surgery.
她应该刚做完手术
So wherever you keep people like that.
应该待在安置术后病人的地方吧
Okay.
我查一下
So it looks like she was moved to the maternity ward last night.
这写着她昨晚被转到了产科病房
- The maternity ward? - Yes.
- 产科病房？ - 是的
- What do you mean, "the maternity ward"? - I'm sorry, I don't know the details.
- 为什么要去产科？ - 抱歉 我不清楚细节
Is she okay? Did she have the baby? She's not due for four weeks.
她没事吧？她生了吗？预产期还有四周啊
This is all the information that I have, that she was rushed--
我只知道 她是被急送过去的...
"Rushed"? What are you saying, "rushed"? First you said, "moved,"
急送？什么意思？还转到了产科
- now you're saying, "rushed"? - Sir, can you please calm down?
- 又急送 什么意思？ - 先生 请您冷静一下
Just put me through to the maternity ward, please.
直接帮我把电话转到产科 谢谢
- Daddy! - Hey!
- 爸爸 - 嘿
Excuse me. Maternity ward's here?
打扰一下 产科的病房在哪儿？
- Yes, down the hall. - Down the hall. Thank you.
- 对 往前走 - 好 往前走 谢谢
- Sir, you need to sign in. - No, no. I'm the father.
- 别走 先签名登记 - 不 不用 我是孩子他爸
Hi.
嗨
（产科病房B）
It's okay, sleep. I'm here. I'm here. It's okay.
没事 睡吧 我在这 我在这 没事的
I'm right here. Don't worry, I'm not going anywhere.
别怕 我不会走的 我哪儿也不去
Go back to sleep.
继续睡吧
I love you.
我爱你
Mizler.
米兹勒的
You said four, right?
四号箱 对吧？
Do you want me to pick him up?
要我抱起来给您看看吗？
Say hi to Daddy.
跟爸爸打个招呼吧
Yeah, there he is. Say hi.
看那是爸爸 叫爸爸
Yes. Yeah.
对 爸爸
♪ Welcome to your life ♪
♪ 欢迎来到这场人生 ♪
♪ There's no turning back ♪
♪ 没有回头的路可走 ♪
♪ Even while we sleep ♪
♪ 即使你在梦中沉睡 ♪
♪ We will find you ♪
♪ 坏事也会不约而至 ♪
字幕译制
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ Acting on your best behaviour ♪
♪ 表面上装得彬彬有礼 ♪
字幕贡献者
翻译/校对/时间轴   小p
后期/翻译/时间轴   NickCollect
校对   Charlie
校对/技术支持   Frank
校对   十三
♪ Turn your back on Mother Nature ♪
♪ 却背弃了良知的呼唤 ♪
CC BY‑NC‑SA 4.0
字幕许可
主 演
提莫西·查拉梅 饰 马蒂·毛瑟
格温妮斯·帕特洛 饰 退休女演员凯·斯通
敖德萨·阿锡安 饰 已婚女性伴侣瑞秋
凯文·奥利里 饰 富商罗克韦尔
泰勒·奥康马 饰 出租车司机沃利
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ It's my own design ♪
♪ 都怪我的选择 ♪
♪ It's my own remorse ♪
♪ 我是自作自受 ♪
♪ Help me to decide ♪
♪ 帮我去决定 ♪
♪ Help me make the ♪
♪ 帮我去得到 ♪
♪ Most of freedom and of pleasure ♪
♪ 那自由和欢乐 ♪
♪ Nothing ever lasts forever ♪
♪ 没什么能永远长存 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ There's a room where the light won't find you ♪
♪ 总有阳光照不到的黑暗 ♪
♪ Holding hands while the walls come tumbling down ♪
♪ 高墙总有崩塌的一天 ♪
♪ When they do, I'll be right behind you ♪
♪ 当这一切发生时 我会站在你身后 ♪
♪ So glad we've almost made it ♪
♪ 庆幸我们走到这一步 ♪
♪ So sad they had to fade it ♪
♪ 遗憾他们必须要放弃 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ I can't stand this indecision ♪
♪ 我受不了这动荡的人生 ♪
♪ Married with a lack of vision ♪
♪ 也受不了被命运套牢 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the— ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰... ♪
♪ Say that you'll never, never, never, never need it ♪
♪ 说你永远 永远 永远不会需要 ♪
♪ One headline, why believe it? ♪
♪ 一个头条 凭什么去相信？ ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ All for freedom and for pleasure ♪
♪ 为了享尽自由和欢乐 ♪
♪ Nothing ever lasts forever ♪
♪ 没什么能永远长存 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
（纽约中央影业）
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by Love
（A24影业）